"家庭是我們民族找尋希望,用翅膀托起夢想的地方."
引自喬治·沃克·布什(小布什)演講
Hey, Brennan.
嘿，布倫南。
Mom, I'm watching the thing
with the lady.
媽，我在看這個...
I'm leaving. Okay?
I'll be home around 1 1.
我要出門了，11左右回來。
-Bye, Mom.
-Bye, Brennan.
—再見，媽。
－再見，布倫南。
Let's slowly get those hips up.
Good. Now, hold it right here. Great.
慢慢的把屁股抬起來。
好，現在，抬到這個位置。好。
Dale.
戴爾。
Dale, I'm leaving for the conference.
戴爾，我要去開會了。
-You leave me money for pizza, Dad?
-Yeah, there's $20 on the hall table.
－爸，你給我留買比薩的錢了嗎？
－留了，在客廳桌子上有20美元。
Do not order pay-per-view, buddy.
不要定制收費節目，老兄。
-But what if I want wings?
-You don't need wings.
－但是如果我想要雞翅呢？
－你不需要雞翅。
That's not enough, Dad!
爸，那根本就不夠！
The RTl cochlear implant...
RTI人工耳蝸...
...is the state-of-the-art
implantable hearing device...
...是一種最先進的可植入助聽設備...
...due to its input processing of sound
via the speech processor.
...鑒於通過語音處理程序對其聲音的輸入加工
But the most exciting
new development...
但是最令人興奮的新研究成果...
...is the external processor...
...是它的外部處理器...
...which fits directly over the ear...
...它可以直接套在耳朵上...
...which eliminates the need to put
your face between those breasts.
...那可以消除把臉放在「胸部」之間的必要。
I'm sorry. I'm just-- I'm so lost.
And this never happens to me.
我很抱歉。我只是有點－我太暈了。
從來沒有過的情況。
My name is Robert, and I play
racquetball. I collect coins.
我叫羅伯特，我玩壁球，收集硬幣。
Sweet Jesus! I love Korean food.
天哪！我喜歡韓國菜。
I am Nancy Huff. I know
how to make tandoori chicken...
我是南希.哈芙。我會做唐杜裡雞（一種印度美食）...
...I contribute to NPR
every single year...
...我每年都為美國公共廣播電台撰稿...
...and I love the movies
of Rob Reiner.
...我還喜歡羅伯·萊納的電影。
Pilates changed my life.
普拉提（一種健身運動）改變了我的生活。
I have a boat, and I wanna retire
and sail around the world.
我有一艘船，
退休後我打算航游世界。
-I love the sea!
-And I drive a Mercedes...
－我喜歡大海！
－我開奔馳...
...and I have a 40-year-old son, Dale,
who still lives at home.
...我還有個40歲的兒子，戴爾，
仍然和我住一起。
-What did you just say?
-I knew I shouldn't have told you that.
－你說什麼？
－我就知道我不應該告訴你這些。
I have a 39-year-old son
named Brennan...
我也有個兒子，39歲了，叫布倫南。
...who still lives at home with me.
...也仍和我住在一起。
I would like to thank all of you...
我要感謝你們所有人...
...for being here with us
on this fantastic, wonderful day.
...在這麼一個美好的日子與我們相伴。
And I would like to raise my glass.
並且我還要舉起我的酒杯。
Dale and I wanna welcome you
to our home with open arms.
戴爾和我張開雙臂歡迎你們的到來。
-Get a room, Dad.
-Oh, for chri-- Dale!
－進洞房吧，爸。
－哦，天哪...     －戴爾
Well, as you all know, my youngest
son, Derek, couldn't be here...
大家都知道，我最小的兒子德裡克
因為一個非常重要的垂釣航行...
...because of an important
fishing trip.
...所以不能到場。
But my other son, Brennan, was going
to be moving into his own place...
但我另一個兒子，布倫南，本要
搬進他自己的房子...
...but he was recently let go
from his job at PetSmart...
...但最近被Petsmart公司解雇了...
...so he is gonna be living with us.
...所以他也將和我們住在一起。
I wasn't fired from my job,
I was laid off!
我不是被解雇了，我是下崗了！
But you wouldn't
know the difference.
你永遠都不會知道這中間的區別的。
I didn't want salmon!
I said it four times.
我不想要鮭魚！
我已經說過四次了。
This wedding is horseshit.
整個婚禮就是垃圾。
Somebody's awfully quiet
back there.
坐在後面的人好安靜啊。
I'm not gonna call him Dad.
我不會喊他父親的。
Brennan, you're 39 years old.
布倫南，你已經39了。
I would not expect you
to call him Dad.
我不指望你叫他父親。
Well, I'm not going to, ever.
Even if there's a fire.
好的，我不會叫他，永遠。
哪怕用槍對著我。
Robert better not get in my face...
羅伯特最好別出現在我面前...
...because I'll drop
that motherfucker.
...否則我會把那個婊子養的給扔下去。
Jesus, Brennan.
天哪，布倫南。
I'm just saying, I think
you gotta think about your options.
我說說而已。我認為你該好好考慮一下你的選擇。
I know that you are
technically married now...
我知道你們現在法律上結婚了...
...but that does not mean
that they have to live here.
...但那並不意味著他們必須要住這兒。
Dale, I think it's time for a change
for both of us.
戴爾，我覺得是時候改變一下我們的生活了。
Dad, we're men, okay?
爸，我們是男人，對嗎？
That means a few things.
那意味著很多事情。
We like to shit with the door open.
We talk about pussy.
我們喜歡開著門大便。
我們談論陰道。
We go on riverboat-gambling trips.
We make our own beef jerky.
我們參加水上賭博。
我們自己製作牛肉乾。
That's what we do.
And now that is all wrecked.
這是我們幹的。
但現在一切都毀了。
We literally have never done
any of those things.
準確來說，我們從來沒有做過這些。
Where did he go to medical school?
他在哪兒上的醫學院？
He went to Northwestern
and Johns Hopkins.
西北大學和約翰霍普金斯大學。
-ls that good enough for you?
-No, it's not.
－是不是很不錯？
－不，沒覺得。
Well, Brennan, those are
very prestigious schools.
好了，布倫南，這些可都是著名大學。
I smoked pot with Johnny Hopkins.
我與約翰霍普金斯一起吸過大煙。
You don't know anyone
named Johnny Hopkins.
你根本就不認識叫約翰霍普金斯的人。
It was Johnny Hopkins
and Sloan Kettering...
那是和約翰霍普金斯和斯隆-凱特林（著名的醫學研究所）
...and they were
blazing that shit up every day.
...他們每天都把大煙燒的很旺。
All right, here's a scenario
for you, Dad.
好吧，爸，現在你面臨著這麼一種局面。
Suppose Nancy sees me
coming out of the shower...
假設南希看到我淋浴出來...
...and decides to come on to me.
I'm looking good.
...並且要和我做愛。
我看起來很不錯的。
I've got a luscious V of hair...
我有著性感的V字胸毛...
...going from my chest pubes
down to my ball-fro.
...從胸部一直到睪丸。
And she takes one look at me,
and she goes:.
然後她看了我一眼，說道：
"Oh, my God.
「哦，天哪。
I've had the old bull,
now I want the young calf."
我已經得到了老牛，
現在我想要嘗嘗小牛的滋味了。」
-And she grabs me by the wiener.
-Shut the fuck up!
－然後她就抓住我的陽物。
－給我他媽的閉嘴！
－來吧，布倫南。
－我在這裡很好。
－你來了。
－嗨。
你穿著運動裝真漂亮。
-How was it?
-lt was easy.
－情況如何?
－很輕鬆。
The movers did everything.
搬運工人包攬了全部。
布倫南在哪？
他還在車裡。
It was kind of a rough drive.
這段車程可有點棘手。
Hey, Robert,
what's all the commotion?
嘿，羅伯特，
這麼亂怎麼回事？
- Hey, Don.
- Is that your wife, Nancy?
－嘿，丹。
－這是你妻子南希嗎？
-Right here, Don.
-Can I come over this afternoon...
－正是我，丹。
－今天下午我能不能過來...
-...and touch your face?
-Sure.
－...拜訪一下你？
－當然可以。
Thanks. Good luck, guys.
謝謝。好運，夥計們。
We'll see you, Don.
回見，丹。
Let's go, Cinnamon.
Heel, Cinnamon.
西納蒙，走了。
跟上，西納蒙。
Heel! Cinnamon!
Cinnamon!
西納蒙。
Hi, Dale.
嗨，戴爾。
Hey, Nancy. Could you make me
a grilled-cheese sandwich?
嘿，南希。你能給我做一個烤奶酪三明治嗎？
- Sure.
- No.
－當然可以。
－不。
Dale just ate. He's testing you to see
how much he can get away with.
戴爾剛剛吃過。
他在試試看能吃到什麼。
- I see.
- I'm hungry.
－我明白。
－我餓。
Look in your right hand.
看看你右手拿的。
-I sure don't mind a bit. I really don't.
-I know, I know.
－我當然不會介意的，真的不會。
－我知道，我知道。
No, no. He's fine.
他沒事的。
Hey.
嘿。
I'm Brennan.
我是布倫南。
I'm Dale.
我是戴爾。
But you have to call me Dragon.
但是你要叫我巨龍。
You have to call me Nighthawk.
你要叫我夜鷹。
Brennan.
布倫南。
Please don't do that.
請別這樣。
Now, that's enough ketchup.
Come on. Dale.
番茄醬夠多了。
別這樣，戴爾。
-I like it.
-That's enough.
－我喜歡番茄醬。
－夠了。
Dale, I don't know if you--
戴爾，我不知道你是否－
You might wanna try this. I make
a sauce, we call it "fancy sauce"...
你可能想試試這個。我做了一種醬，
我們稱它為「怪味醬」...
For me.
為我。
--that Brennan really likes
with his chicken nuggets.
－布倫南真的非常喜歡雞塊蘸著吃。
It's my fancy sauce.
那是我的怪味醬。
Well, when Brennan finishes,
I'll give you some of this, and it's...
嗯，布倫南用完了，我給你些嘗嘗，它是...
It's ketchup and mayonnaise
mixed together, so....
它是番茄醬和蛋黃醬混合而成的，所以...
It's so good.
味道很不錯。
-I want some fancy sauce.
-Yeah.
－我想要一些怪味醬。
－好的。
-I'm not done using it.
-Looks good.
－我還沒用完。
－看起來不錯。
-Can I have fancy sauce?
-Of course. Of course.
－我能吃一些怪味醬嗎？
－當然，當然。
-I'm using it right now.
-Okay.
－我現在正用著呢。
－好的。
-So let's just let him try some.
-You wanna try it, Dale?
－讓他嘗一些。
－你想嘗一下嗎，戴爾？
Yeah, I really would like some.
是的，我真的想要一些。
Just one last spoonful.
再要最後一勺。
Hey, I think you've got
enough there, Brennan.
嘿，你那已經夠多了，布倫南。
It's ketchup and mayonnaise.
這是番茄醬和蛋黃醬。
-I don't like it. It smells weird.
-Okay.
－我不喜歡，聞起來怪怪的。
－好的。
-I'll try some.
-You want some?
－我要嘗一下。
－你想要嘗一下？
-Sure. Absolutely.
-Okay.
－當然。
－好。
You don't mind, do you, Brennan?
No. Okay.
布倫南，你不介意吧？
不，好。
-Brennan--
-I'm not comfortable--
－布倫南...
－我不舒服...
It's okay. It's probably
not good on fish anyway.
沒事的。可能是魚吃的不舒服了。
My dad's king of the castle, so if he
wants fancy sauce, he should--
這是我爸的地盤，所以如果他想要怪味醬，他就應該...
-No, it's all right, Dale.
-He can make his own batch.
－不，沒關係的，戴爾。
－他可以自己做他那份。
So you know what?
你知道嗎？
Today, when you were driving around,
Dale was telling me that he's really...
今天當你開車出去的時候，戴爾告訴我他非常...
...into kung fu, and I was telling him
that you're really into kung fu as well.
...喜歡功夫，我告訴他你也真的很喜歡功夫。
I have a green belt.
我有一條綠腰帶。
Read it and weep.
明白就哭去吧。
I don't believe in belts.
我不相信腰帶等級。
There should be no
ranking system for toughness.
健壯應該沒什麼等級。
But one time I wrestled a giraffe
to the ground with my bare hands.
但是一次我赤手空拳把一頭長頸鹿摔倒在地。
That's not true, Dale.
Don't be ridiculous.
那不是真的，戴爾。
別荒唐了。
So, Dale, what have you been
working on recently?
那，戴爾，最近忙些什麼？
Well...
嗯...
...I manage a baseball team.
...我管著一個棒球隊。
-Little League?
-Fantasy league.
－小聯盟？
－幻想聯盟。
Take a picture. It'll last longer.
拍張照片，那會持續的時間長些。
Why don't you stop
being so confrontational, Dale?
別再那麼有敵意了，戴爾。
I'm not the one staring at me.
盯著我看的不是我。
So, Brennan, how about you?
布倫南，你呢？
I know you used to
work at PetSmart.
我知道你過去在PetSmart工作。
-That's right, Mr. Doback.
-Call me Robert.
－對了，多巴克先生。
－叫我羅伯特。
-That's right, Robin.
-Robert.
－好的，羅賓。
－羅伯特。
Robin.
羅賓。
Actually, Brennan
is a really talented person.
事實上，布倫南是一個很有天賦的人。
He's a very gifted singer.
他是一個很有天賦的歌手。
-I'm really, really good.
-How good?
－我真的真的很不錯。
－有多好？
I've been called
the songbird of my generation...
那些聽過我唱歌的人...
...by people who've heard me.
...稱我為鳴禽。
That good.
就那麼好。
The only trick is
is that Brennan's very...
布倫南唯一的毛病就是他對...
...particular about
who he sings in front of, so....
...在誰面前唱非常挑剔，所以...
I'm his mom, for example,
I've only heard him sing twice.
比如，我是他母親，
但也只聽他唱過兩次。
That's funny that you say that,
because I can sing too.
你說那太滑稽了，因為我也能唱。
In fact, I'll sing right now.
事實上，我馬上就會唱。
If you wanna get down
On these hairy balls
歌詞：如果你想騎到我的睪丸上
-Hey!
-Why don't you jump right in?
－嘿！
－（歌詞：）你為什麼不跳進來？
It's a crotch party right up in here
（歌詞）這裡正開褲襠晚會
-Stop it!
-Why don't you lick on this big joint?
－住嘴！
－（歌詞：）你為什麼不舔舔我這裡？
Stop it, Dale! Stop it! Stop it!
停，戴爾！停！停！
That's cute.
有意思。
I remember when I had my first beer.
讓我想起了我第一次喝啤酒的時候。
That's so funny,
the last time I heard that...
很有趣，自從上次我從恐龍上摔下來後...
...I laughed so hard
I fell off my dinosaur.
...我就沒有笑的如此開心過。
Stop right now. All right?
Let's just back off.
閉嘴。好嗎？
讓我們都退一步。
All right. Brennan, it's okay.
It's okay.
好了。布倫南，沒事了。
沒事了。
Hey, hey.
嘿，嘿。
-Great, Dale.
-He said a mean thing first.
－好了，戴爾。
－是他先挑頭說的。
All right, just--
Look, you know what--? Hey, guys.
好了，只是---
聽著，你知道---？嘿，夥計們。
Okay, sleeping arrangements.
It's gonna be different...
好，睡覺安排。做些調整...
...but because Dale refuses
to give up his office drum set...
...因為戴爾不願意放棄他的練鼓房...
...that means that, Brennan, you and
Dale are gonna have to share a room.
...那就意味著，布倫南，你和戴爾將不得不共享一室。
-But it's just temporary.
-Mom, we didn't talk about this.
－但那只是暫時的。
－媽媽，你沒有給我說過這些。
Well, it's gonna be
an exciting adventure.
嗯，那將會是一次非常刺激的經歷。
You wanna show him the room, Dale?
Show him where he can put his stuff?
戴爾，你難道不想帶他看看房間嗎？
看看他能把東西放哪兒？
-That's nice, thank you.
-Good night, Nancy.
－不錯，謝謝。
－晚安，南希。
Hey, listen, I like to have
a lot of fresh fruit around...
嘿，聽著，我喜歡到處有很多新鮮水果...
...and chocolate chips
in my pancakes. Okay?
...和很多巧克力片的煎餅。好嗎？
-Write it so you don't forget.
-Show him the room.
－把它寫下來，這樣你就不會忘了。
－帶他看看房間。
She's Mom now, so...
她現在是媽媽了，所以...
-Good night, Mom.
-Good night, Brennan.
-晚安，媽媽。
－晚安，布倫南。
-Good night, Mr. Doback.
-Good night, Brennan.
－晚安，多巴克先生。
－晚安，布倫南。
So just a few basic rules
about the house.
關於房子有一些基本規矩。
If there's any foods that you like...
假如有任何你不喜歡的食物...
...I suggest you put your name
on them, or they will be thrown out.
...我建議你寫上名字，否則它們會被扔出去。
By me.
被我扔出去。
House was built in 1 825
by General Custer.
房子由卡思特將軍建於1825年。
I wanna show you this room.
我想帶你看看這個房間。
Hold up.
停下。
-You see this room?
-Yeah.
－你看到這個房間了？
－是的。
Okay, here's the deal.
好，這是協議。
This is my office
and my beat laboratory.
這是我的辦公室兼練鼓房。
Okay?
聽明白了？
And this is the one rule of the house:.
房子的規矩：
Don't ever, ever, ever...
永遠，永遠都不要...
...touch my drum set.
...碰我的鼓。
-You understand?
-Don't go in there and--
－明白了嗎？
－不要進去和...
-No touching!
-All right!
－不准碰！
－好！
There. I was at about six there.
我六點來這裡。
You don't wanna see me go to 1 0.
十點之前別想見我。
Get your shit.
We're going to my room.
帶著你的東西。
來看看我的房間。
Honey?
親愛的？
I just found a chain of islands
that we can sail to after New Zealand.
我剛剛發現一些小島，
去過新西蘭以後我們航行到那裡。
That's wonderful.
太棒了！
You know,
I've been meaning to ask you....
你知道，我一直都想問你...
Why is it that Dale never left?
為什麼戴爾沒有搬出去？
Well, Dale has always
coasted off my accomplishments.
嗯，戴爾一直都指望我的成就過活。
I mean, he left college
his junior year...
我的意思是，他大三的時候退學...
...because he said he wanted
to join the family business.
...因為他說他想加入家族產業。
-But you're a medical doctor.
-Believe me, I've told him that.
－但你是個醫生。
－相信我，我告訴過他。
But he just always says,
"It's all about who you know."
但他總是說：「我就是這個樣子」。
I don't know where
he got this sense of entitlement.
我不知道他從哪得到的權利意識。
Maybe it was his mother passing.
What about Brennan?
也許是從他媽那裡。
布倫南怎麼回事？
From what you've told me...
你告訴過我...
...his younger brother Derek's
been quite successful.
...他弟弟德裡克很成功。
Well, certainly when his father
and I split, that was difficult for him.
唔，無疑我和他父親的分手使他很難接受。
And this one time, when Brennan
was 1 7 and Derek was 1 4...
那時，布倫南17，德裡克14...
...and Brennan decided
to enter a talent show.
...布倫南決定要參加一個才能展示...
He sang a song
from an old pirate musical.
他唱了一部老海盜音樂劇中的一首歌。
But Derek got his football buddies
to replace the choir and sing:
但是德裡克和他的一幫足球哥們
代替了合唱團並唱到：
"Brennan has a mangina."
「布倫南有個女人的下體。」
Brennan has a mangina
「布倫南有個女人的下體。」「布倫南有個女人的下體。」
Finally, the audience and even some
of the nastier parents started singing:
後來，觀眾，甚至一些惡意的父母也開始唱：
"Brennan has a mangina."
「布倫南有個女人的下體。」
And I have to admit, for a little while,
I sort of joined in as well.
我必須承認，我也唱了一會。
From that day on,
Brennan never sang again.
從那天後，布倫南就再也沒有唱過。
Derek went on to win the contest
by lip-synching "lce lce Baby."
德裡克則通過假唱「lce lce Baby」贏得了比賽。
-Oh, that's a great song.
-lt is.
－哦，一首很了不起的歌。
－確實。
-Hey, you awake?
-Yeah.
－嘿，你醒著了嗎？
－是的。
I just want you to know I hate you.
So does my dad.
我只是想讓你知道我恨你。
我父親也一樣恨你。
Well, that's fine.
唔，很好。
Because guess what.
猜猜為什麼。
I hate you too.
因為我也恨你。
And this house sucks ass.
還有這房子讓人噁心。
Well, the only reason
you're living here...
噢，你住在這裡的唯一理由就是...
...is because me and my dad decided
that your mom was really hot...
...因為我和我父親覺得你母親真的很熱辣...
...and maybe we should just
both bang her.
...也許我們都可以幹她。
And we'll put up with the retard
in the meantime.
同時我們要忍受那個智障。
-Who's the retard?
-You.
－那個智障是誰？
－你。
-Hey, y'all don't say that.
-Shut up.
－嘿，不許那樣說。
－閉嘴。
You'll wake up my dad
and get me grounded.
你會把我父親吵醒的
他又會罰我不許出門了。
Just shut up.
那就閉嘴。
You and your mom are hillbillies.
你和你母親都是鄉巴佬。
-This is a house of learned doctors.
-You're not a doctor.
－這是博學的醫生住的的房子。
－可你不是醫生。
You're a big, fat, curly-headed fuck.
你就是一個肥胖的，滿頭卷髮的混蛋。
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
－噢，是嗎？
－是。
-I'm a curly-headed fuck?
-Yeah.
－我是一個滿頭卷髮的混蛋？
－是的。
You better not go to sleep.
你最好別睡覺。
As soon as your eyes shut, I'm gonna
punch you square in the face.
你一閉眼，我就會把你的臉打扁的。
I hope you stay still
when you sleep...
我希望你睡著的時候別動...
...because I'm putting a rat trap
between your legs.
...因為我會把一個老鼠夾子放在你兩腿之間。
I'm gonna take a pillowcase
and fill it full of bars of soap...
我會拿個枕套，裡面裝滿肥皂塊...
...and beat the shit out of you.
...打得你屁滾尿流。
I want you out of my fucking house.
我想讓你滾出這個房子。
No way, kemosabe.
沒門，忠實的朋友。
This is my house now.
現在這是我的房子。
How do you like The Gilded Lady?
你覺得Gilded Lady（船名）如何？
I wish we could retire right now.
我真我現在就能退休。
Won't be long.
很快的。
Oh, God! It's cold!
噢，天哪！好冷！
Hey! Is anyone listening? Help!
嘿，有人聽見沒？救命！
「我愛冰毒。」
Fuck you, Dale! Fuck you!
去你媽的，戴爾！去你媽的！
--obviously you guys are hot.
You know?
（電視：）－顯然你們這些傢伙都很高明。
你知道嗎？
Just revealed her cover.
I was like, "Wow, this is hot. "
翻開封面。我就會：「哇，很熱辣。」
A little girl-on-girl.
A little heaven, a little hell.
有點女同性戀味道。
一半是天堂，一半是地獄。
-Hey.
－嘿。
-Why you so sweaty?
-I was watching Cops.
－你為什麼大汗淋漓？
－我剛才在看《警察》。
Not supposed to have
your feet on the couch.
你不應該把腳放在沙發上。
Hey, man.
嘿，老兄 。
Did you touch my drum set?
你動我的鼓了嗎？
-Nope.
-It's just weird...
－沒。
－很奇怪...
...because seems like someone
definitely touched my drum set.
...因為看起來肯定有人動了我的鼓。
Yeah, that is weird.
Because I didn't touch them.
是啊，很奇怪。
因為我沒有碰。
-Hey! Did you touch my drum set?
-Hey, knock it off!
－嘿！你動我的鼓了嗎？
－嘿，別胡鬧了！
I know you touched my drumstick,
because the left one has a chip in it.
我知道你動了我的鼓，
因為左邊的上面有個缺口。
You fucking crazy, man?
你瘋了吧，老兄？
You sound insane, do you realize
that? You should be medicated.
你聽起來瘋了，沒意識到嗎？
你應該接受藥物治療。
Fuck you, Brennan.
I know you touched my drum set.
去你媽的，布倫南。
我知道你動了我的鼓。
I wanna hear that
dirty mouth admit it.
我想聽到你那骯髒的嘴親口承認。
You get out of my face,
or I'm gonna roundhouse your ass.
滾，否則我掄你屁股。
You swear on your mom's life
that you didn't touch it!
你以你媽媽的性命發誓你沒有動它！
I don't swear to shit!
我不向卑鄙小人發誓！
That's because you fucking
touched my drum set...
那時因為你丫的動了我的鼓...
...because I know
Cops doesn't start till 4.
...因為我知道《警察》到4點才開始。
-Where are you going?
-I'm going upstairs.
－你去哪？
－上樓。
Because I'm gonna put my nut sack
on your drum set. Okay?
我要把我的陰囊放到你的鼓上。可以了吧？
Don't you do that.
I am warning you right now:.
別那樣做。
我現在警告你：
If you touch my drums, I will
stab you in the neck with a knife!
假如你動了我的鼓，我會拿刀子抹了你的脖子。
If you even go in the room,
I will go ape-shit, you hear me?
即使你踏進那個房間，
我都會不客氣的，聽到了沒？
Don't wanna miss a spot.
別想放過一個地方。
John Bonham's playing
"Moby Dick" for real!
約翰.博納姆（一著名鼓手）在真實表演Moby Dick！
I swear to God. I swear to God! No!
我對天發誓。我對天發誓！不！
I warned you.
我警告過你。
There's one rule in the house,
and you broke it!
這是房子規矩，你壞了規矩！
I didn't touch your damn drum set!
我沒有碰你該死的鼓！
I'm pre-diabetic!
我有前期糖尿病。
You fucking fucker! I'm gonna
rub my balls on your mom's face!
你他媽的混蛋！我要用我的睪丸擦你媽的臉！
Come back here!
回來！
I'll kill you! You son of a bitch!
我要殺了你!你這婊子養的！
Your drum set's a whore!
你的鼓就是個蕩婦！
I teabagged your fucking drum set!
我要泡她！
Well, my drum set's a guy,
so that makes you gay, you fucker!
我的鼓是個男人，你就是個同性戀，你這混蛋！
I'll kill you!
我要殺了你！
I think it's gonna go
generic soon, okay?
我認為那很快就會變的很普通的，不是嗎？
-Line three.
-Oh, thanks, Miles.
－三號線。
－哦，謝謝你，邁爾斯。
Yeah.
是的。
Jules? Wait, what's wrong?
朱爾斯？等一下，怎麼回事？
-Back!
-You touched my drum set, you fucker!
－退後！
－你動了我的鼓，你這混蛋！
Stop it! Stop it!
住手！住手！
-Rape! Rape! Rape!
-Stop it! Stop! Stop.
－強姦了！強姦了！強姦了！
－住手！住手！住手！
-Stay out of this, Nancy!
-Stop it, you guys.
－南希，你別管！
－住手，你們兩個傢伙.
-Oh, my God, you're hurting him!
-No, Nancy!
－哦，天哪，你傷著他了！
－不，南希！
Cinnamon! Stop it!
西納蒙！住手！
My mom is being eaten by a dog,
there's nothing I can do!
一隻狗在咬我媽媽，
而我卻無能為力！
-No, a story has a....
-Excuse me.
－不，一個故事有一個...
－很抱歉。
Dr. Doback, the phone's for you.
I think it's urgent.
多巴克醫生，你的電話。
我認為可能是急事。
Hello?
喂？
Robert, they're like animals!
I can't stop them!
羅伯特，他們就是野獸一樣！
我無法阻止他們！
Stop screaming. Please.
I'm on my way.
請別叫。我馬上來。
There seems to be some
savage fight going on...
看起來正在進行一場兇猛的戰鬥...
...between my son and stepson,
so l--
...在我兒子和繼子之間，所以我－－
Family issues, huh?
家庭糾紛，啊？
I don't believe in talking about
people's personal lives...
我不贊成談論別人的私生活...
...behind their back.
...在別人背後。
You know nobody likes you, right?
你知道沒人喜歡你，對嗎？
Rape! Rape! Rape!
強姦了！強姦了!強姦了！
What's going on?
發生什麼事了？
Robert! They won't-- They won't--
羅伯特！他們不－他們不－－
-Stop it! Stop it!
-Dale, what--?
－住手！住手！
－戴爾，怎麼－？
-Stay out of it, Dad!
-Stop it!
－爸，你別管！
－住手！
What the fucking fuck?
到底他媽的怎麼了？
Someone got some air. Snap.
有條鯊魚需要空氣了。擊掌。
-I still hate you.
-Still hate you.
－我仍然恨你。
－我也仍然恨你。
Such power. It's raw power.
看那力量。原生力量。
What are you doing?
It's Shark Week.
你在幹什麼？正在放《鯊魚星期》呢。
Okay, here's the deal:
好了，這是協議：
Number one, you will fix
the fucking drywall now.
第一條：你們現在要把干砌牆修好。
Number two, you have one month to
find jobs or you're out on your asses.
第二條：給你們一個月的時間找工作，否則就滾蛋。
I will arrange interviews for Monday,
and you will go!
我會安排星期一的面試，你去！
Dad, why are you talking
to me like this? I'm your son.
爸，你為什麼這樣和我說話？我是你兒子。
I'm not buying that crap anymore.
我再也不會相信你的胡扯了。
Today I saw my own son
use a bicycle as a weapon.
今天我看見我自己的兒子用一輛自行車做武器。
You yelled "rape"
at the top of your lungs.
你歇斯底里地高喊「強姦」。
Mom, I honestly thought
I was gonna be raped for a second.
媽媽，我當時真的認為自己要被再一次強姦了。
He had the craziest look in his eyes.
他的眼神太瘋狂了。
And at one point he said,
"Let's get it on."
他一度還說：「讓我們繼續干吧。」
That was about the fighting.
I'm so not a raper.
那是關於打架。我不是個強姦犯。
I didn't touch your drum set, okay?
我沒有動你的鼓，行了吧？
I witnessed with my eyes
your testicles touching my drum set.
我親眼所見你用睪丸擦我的鼓了。
All right, that's it! That's it!
好了，夠了！夠了！
You two guys leave me no choice.
你們倆個讓我無法選擇。
No television for a week.
一個星期不准看電視。
-What?!
－什麼？！
-We are so serious, guys.
-You're fucking high!
－我們是認真的，夥計們。
－你們太變態了！
Are you out of your mind?
你瘋了？
This goes in Robert's wall safe
and it's gonna stay there.
這在羅伯特的房子裡執行
並將一直有效。
-No!
-Okay.
－不！
－好了！
-This house is a fucking prison!
-On planet Bullshit!
－這個房子就是他媽的一個監獄！
－狗屁星球！
In the galaxy of
This Sucks Camel Dicks!
在狗屎星系！
Hi! Aunt Carol. Aunt Carol.
嗨！開羅阿姨。開羅阿姨。
-Hey.
-You can't catch me.
－嘿。
－你抓不著我。
I gotcha.
我抓住你了。
Aunt Carol's on fire!
開羅阿姨著火了！
I don't know where you learned it.
我不知道你在哪學的這個。
-Well, there's lots more where that--
-My God.
－唔，還有很多你....
－天哪。
-Oh, no. What happened?
-What the--?
－哦，不。發生了什麼？
－什麼？
Oh, my God.
哦，天哪。
Maybe Dale left the back door open
and raccoons got in.
可能是戴爾沒有關後門浣熊闖進來了。
Nancy? Is this your purse
in the freezer?
南希，冰櫃裡的包是你的嗎？
Yes. It's Brennan.
是的。是布倫南干的。
He sleepwalks and he always
puts my purse in the freezer.
他夢遊並且總是把我的包放到冰櫃裡。
Dale sleepwalks too.
戴爾也夢遊。
-Are you kidding me?
-I'm not. Look in the oven.
－你在開玩笑？
－不，看看烤箱裡面。
-What's in the--? Couch pillows?
-Couch pillows.
－裡面有什麼...?沙發靠墊？
－沙發靠墊。
Yeah, Dale.
是的，戴爾。
Come on.
別這樣。
-It's okay.
-It's really hard.
－沒事的。
－這太難了。
It's gonna be fine.
一切都會好起來的。
They're gonna get jobs,
they'll be gone in a month. A month.
他們要去找工作了，一個月之後他們就要
搬出去了。一個月!
Guys.
夥計們。
-Guys. Guys!
-I'll kill you, Leonard Nimoy.
－夥計們。夥計們！
－我要殺了你，倫納德.尼莫依。
The clown has no penis.
那個小丑沒有陰莖。
What kind of dreams
are you guys having?
你們都做了什麼夢？
Hey, it's 1 2:30.
嘿，現在12：30了。
Brennan, your brother's
coming today, so get up.
布倫南，你弟弟今天要來，所以趕緊起來。
-Today?
-Yep.
－今天？
－是的。
-Shit.
-What's your problem?
－媽的。
－怎麼了？
My little brother's even
a bigger asshole than you are.
我弟弟甚至比你更混蛋。
All right, let's really nail it this time.
Here we go.
好了，這次讓我們唱好它。
開始。
A one, a two, a one, two, three, four.
一，二，一，二，三，四。
All right, Tommy, you're the oldest.
I'm counting on you. Come on.
好，湯米，你是老大。
我指望你了。來吧。
Nice vibrato, buddy.
All right, all right, Alice, let's go.
顫音不錯，兒子。
好，好，愛麗斯，我們開始。
Flat. It's so flat.
音低了，太低了。
I can't even-- You don't even
look good while you're singing.
我甚至都不能...
你唱的時候看起來就很糟糕。
The worst thing I've ever heard.
我聽過最糟糕的。
This is $1 200 a week for
voice lessons, and this is what I get?
一個星期要付1200美元的聲樂課程，
看看我得到了什麼？
Okay, I'm gonna save it
with this solo.
好吧，我要用獨奏來挽救這支歌。
I'm Derek
我是德裡克。
And I can sing high like this
我能飆的這麼高。
And I can sing high
我能飆的很高。
Jesus!
上帝！
We were so sad you guys
couldn't come to the wedding.
你們沒來參加婚禮我們很難過。
-But we completely understand.
-Yeah.
－但是我們完全理解。
－是的。
You were busy fishing
with Mark Cuban.
你們當時正和馬克-庫班（一個億萬富豪）釣魚。
Oh, yeah, yeah.
Well, not just the Cubes...
哦，是的，是的，
不僅僅是庫班家...
...but we had Chris Daughtry,
Jeff Probst, super-chef Bobby Flay.
...還有克裡斯.道奇、傑夫·普羅斯特和超級廚師博比.付雷。
It was insane.
I mean, it was almost too much.
很瘋狂。
我的意思是，幾乎是太多了。
My God, that's impressive.
我的天哪，太棒了。
Yeah, we were down in the Gulf,
fishing bonito.
是的，我們在海灣下去，釣鰹魚。
Robert, have you ever been down
to the Gulf on the bonito run?
羅伯特，你到過鰹魚航道上的海灣嗎？
Always wanted to.
I hear it's amazing.
一直想去。聽說很令人稱奇。
-lt is. It's gorgeous.
-Are bonito fish big?
－是的，確實很美妙。
－鰹魚很大嗎？
What?
什麼？
Don't interrupt
when he's telling a story.
他在講的時候不要插嘴。
-It's fine, Robert.
-I was asking about the story.
－沒關係的，羅伯特。
－我在問剛才的事情。
-What's this guy's deal?
-I don't know, son. It's okay.
－這傢伙是幹什麼的？
－我不知道，兒子。沒關係。
Well, Dale, they are
what's called a trophy fish.
好的，戴爾，他們被稱之為獎品魚。
So, yeah, they're pretty big.
所以，是的，很大。
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉。
Anyway....
不管怎樣...
Oh, God, I'm sorry,
I forget where my story was going.
哦，天哪，我很抱歉。
我忘了我的故事講到哪兒了。
Damn it, Dale.
該死，戴爾。
-No--
-Robert.
－不－
－羅伯特。
-What?
-What? I asked him.
－什麼？
－什麼？我告訴過他了。
No, he can join in, Robert.
It's really okay.
不，他可以加入，羅伯特。
那真的沒關係。
Well, I asked him twice
not to interrupt.
哦，我告訴過他兩次了不要插嘴。
Gang, don't be mad at Dale for ruining
the story. And possibly the evening.
大家不要怪戴爾把整個故事給毀了
可能整個晚上。
It's totally fine.
I have a lot more stories.
完全沒關係。
我還有很多其它的故事。
-Derek, that you do. That you do.
-Yeah.
－德裡克，你確實有，確實有。
－是的。
-Guilty as charged with the stories.
-Oh, God, you're impressive.
－多的都被控告有罪了。
－哦，天哪，你真討人喜歡。
Come on. I love talking to you.
來吧，我喜歡和你說話。
From across the room,
I feel like we have a thing.
從踏進這個房間我就
覺得我們有共同之處。
You and me, man. You're my
new stepdad. You're unbelievable.
你和我，老兄。你是我的繼父。
你真是不可思議。
-I never heard that laugh before.
-Dad, why are you acting so weird?
－我以前從來沒有聽你這樣笑過。
－爸，今天你為什麼如此奇怪？
Oh, hey, by the way, guys,
where's my bro, Brennan?
哦，嘿，對了，夥計們，我哥哥布倫南在哪？
You're right about your brother.
Total dick.
關於你弟弟，你說的完全正確。
整個一垃圾。
Told you.
早就告訴過你。
You know what? I still hate you...
你知道嗎？我仍然恨你...
...but you got a pretty awesome
collection of nudie mags.
...但是你收集了那麼多黃色雜誌。
Yeah, I got them
from the '70s, '80s and '90s.
是的，70年代、80年代和90年代的我都收集了。
It's like masturbating
in a time machine.
就像在一個時間機器裡手淫。
Anyway, so I figure by the summer
of 201 0, we can probably set sail.
不管怎樣，我算著到2010年的夏天
我們就有可能開航了。
But I think about it
every day of my life.
但是我每天都在想著這個事。
Let me ask you this, Bob,
why wait two years?
鮑勃，我想問問，你為什麼要等兩年呢？
-Well, I gotta make more money.
-Okay, look.
－唔，我要多掙點錢。
－好，聽著。
I hear you, believe me.
我明白你的意思了，相信我。
But what if I were to tell you
that I could sell this house...
但是如果我告訴你我可以賣這房子...
...for 30 percent above market?
...高出市場價的30％，怎麼樣？
-That'd be great. Could you do it?
-Yeah. In a heartbeat, Robby.
－太棒了，你能做到嗎？
－是的。很快，羅比。
Look, I got my real-estate license
a few years back for shits and gigs.
聽著，幾年前因為工作需要我取得了房產執照。
I'd do it for four-fifths commish...
我只收取五分之四的佣金...
...because you know what really
gets my dick hard?
...你知道什麼使我混的這麼好嗎？
Helping out my friends.
幫助我的朋友擺脫困境。
That'd be fantastic.
That'd be fanta-- Oh, my God.
那將太棒了。
太...哦，我的上帝。
-No, it would be kick-ass, bro.
-Oh, man.
－不，老兄，那就太棒了。
－哦，老弟。
Right there.
這裡。
What about Dale and Brennan?
戴爾和布倫南怎麼辦？
Because they haven't
even gotten jobs yet.
他們甚至還沒有找到工作。
God, change the record.
天，情況有變。
Sweet!
爽！
Robert. Don't talk to me like that
in front of my son.
羅伯特，別在我兒子面前那樣對我說話。
Oh, come on. We're talking about
our dream, the boat. Come on.
噢，得了。我們在談論我們的夢想，船。算了吧。
Yeah, it's our dream, but I think it
all needs to be done in good time.
是，那是我們的夢想，但是我認為那需要正確的時機。
I'm just saying give it some thought,
okay? That's it. That's all I'm saying.
我只是說說一些想法，不是嗎？
就這些，我說的就這些。
Holy shit, triplets.
該死，三胞胎。
It's true, three's company.
真是的，三人成伴。
-lt shows tons of bush.
-Hey, hey, careful.
－露了那麼多的陰毛。
－嘿，嘿，小心點。
Careful with that. You're crinkling.
小心點，你都弄皺了。
That's a collector's item.
It's worth a lot of money.
這是收藏品。值很多錢的。
What's up, faggots?
幹什麼呢，「同志」們？
What's up, man? What, you're not
gonna come down, say hi to me?
幹什麼呢,老兄？你不打算下來和我打聲招呼嗎？
Hi, Derek.
嗨，德裡克。
Whoa, calm down, man.
I'm just joking.
噢，冷靜，老兄。我只是開個玩笑。
You guys, I really like
your guys' setup up here.
哇，夥計們，我真的很喜歡你們這個房子。
What is your problem, man?
你有什麼毛病，老弟？
My problem? I don't know.
I don't have a problem, Dale.
毛病？我不知道。我沒有毛病，戴爾。
Actually, I have the opposite
of a problem:
事實上，正好相反：
I made over 550 K last year.
How much did you make?
我去年掙了55萬美元，你呢？
-It's not about money.
-No, it's not about money.
－那不是錢的問題。
－對，那不是錢的問題。
Well, for me,
it's a little bit about money...
哦，對於我來講，那就是和錢有關...
...and I made
that much money last year.
...我去年掙了那麼多錢。
I am the VP of the biggest...
我是西部海岸最大的...
...executive-helicopter-leasing
company on the Western Seaboard.
...豪華直升機租賃公司的副總裁。
Okay? I haven't had a carb
since 2004.
不錯吧？自從2004年以來我就沒有喝過碳化飲料。
Check these out. See these?
See these boys?
核實一下。看到了嗎？
看到這些肌肉了沒？
This is what I live with.
這就是我的生活。
Every day I lather this up
with Kiehl's in the shower.
每天淋浴的時候我都塗滿Kiehl's牌的皂沫。
You wanna touch this shit?
You wanna touch these bad boys?
要不要摸摸？
想要摸摸這些肌肉嗎？
Sorry, not gonna happen.
對不起，說著玩的。
Is there something you want?
你有什麼事？
I promised Mom I'd offer you a job.
我答應媽媽我將會提供給你一份工作。
I told her it'd count as her
Christmas present, so....
我告訴她這算是我送給她的聖誕節禮物，所以...
No. I'm never gonna work for you.
不。我永遠都不會為你工作的。
Fine. I don't care.
好吧。我不在乎。
The truth is I just smoked a J
out in my car a few minutes ago...
事實是，幾分鐘前我在我的車裡吸了一支大麻...
...so feeling a little spacy.
...所以感覺有點輕飄飄的。
Know what I'm say--?
What's up with you, man?
知道我在說什麼嗎？
怎麼了，老兄？
What you looking at, kemosabe?
你在看什麼，朋友？
You--
你...
You wanna punch me right now.
你想馬上揍我一頓。
You wanna punch me right now,
but you won't.
你想馬上揍我一頓，但你不會。
You wanna punch me too?
你也想揍我一頓嗎？
You guys both look like you might
wanna hit me in the face.
你們看起來好像你們可能要給我的臉一拳。
You do, I can tell.
Well, why don't you do it?
你們確實，我能看出來。
好，你們為什麼不動手呢？
Why don't you punch me
in the face?
你們為什麼不揍我的臉一拳？
Punch me in the fucking face!
給我的臉一拳！
-Oh, shit.
-Oh, my shoulder!
－哦，該死。
－哦，我的肩！
That was awesome.
太棒了。
Mom! Mom!
媽！媽！
Derek, know what's always good
for shoulder pain?
德裡克，知道什麼對肩膀疼最有效嗎？
-What?
-lf you lick my butthole.
－什麼？
－舔我的煙巴。
擊掌!
-Thanks, Mom. Thanks, Bobby.
-Sure.
－謝謝媽媽。謝謝，羅比。
－這是應該的。
Aside from that retard trying to punch
me, it was a pretty good evening.
拋開那個蠢貨想揍我不談，這真是一個美好的夜晚。
-lt was our pleasure, son.
-Why are you calling him that?
－別客氣，兒子。
－你為什麼那樣喊他？
Oh, don't, don't.
哦，別問了，別問了。
Bye, kids. I'll check out that stock
you recommended, Tommy.
再見，孩子們。我會看看你推薦的那支股票的，湯米。
Excuse me.
打擾。
-Hi. I'm Alice, I'm Derek's wife.
-Hi.
－嗨，我是愛麗斯，德裡克的妻子。
－嗨。
Is it true you struck Derek in the face
and he fell from the tree house?
你真的打了他臉並且他從樹房上摔了下來？
Yeah. He asked me to.
是的，他要我那樣做的。
Oh, that's the most amazing thing
I've ever heard.
哦，這是我聽過的最美妙的事情。
I want you to know that tonight...
我想讓你知道今天晚上...
...I am gonna pleasure myself to
the image of you doing that to Derek.
...我將靠想像那幅畫面來作樂了。
You know what I mean?
你明白我的意思嗎？
Masturbate.
手淫。
I am.
是的。
Oh, Dale.
哦，戴爾。
You are something.
你真了不起。
You're something too.
你也很了不起。
I wanna roll you into a little ball
and shove you up my vagina.
我想把你捲成一個小球，讓你撞擊我的陰道。
You could just live there.
It's warm and it's cozy.
你可以住在那兒，溫暖而又舒適。
In your vagina?
在你的陰道裡？
I wanna walk around with you
in there and just know that...
我想和你在那裡四處走走，然後...
...whenever I feel a little tickle
or scratch...
...無論什麼時候我覺得有點癢...
...that it's just your hair
up my vagina.
...我就知道那是你的毛髮在我的陰道裡。
Please, just do it for me.
求求你，為我那樣做吧。
What's happening?
發生了什麼事情？
Kiss me.
吻我。
I know. I know. It's too much.
我知道。我知道。那太過分了。
It's too much.
那太過分了。
I hate my life, Dale.
我恨我的生活，戴爾。
Dale, I hate my life!
I have nobody to talk to.
戴爾，我恨我的生活！
我沒有個可以說話的人。
-Well, you seemed okay at the di--
-Please.
－唔，你在餐桌上看起來還不錯--
－求求你。
Alice! Honey, come on!
愛麗斯！親愛的，快點！
Dane Cook, pay-per-view,
20 minutes. Let's go!
戴恩·庫克，收費節目，20分鐘。
我們走了。
Coming, honey!
I'm just talking to Dale.
來了，親愛的！
我在和戴爾說話。
This is so stupid.
這太糟糕了。
Call me.
給我打電話。
-I love you.
-Okay.
－我愛你。
－好。
-Hey. What'd she want?
-What?
－嘿，她要幹什麼？
－什麼？
Nothing. Who's--? Who?
沒什麼。誰要--？誰？
Alice.
愛麗斯。
We were just talking. Not--
It was not about sex or anything.
我們只是在談話。沒有--
沒有涉及性之類的東西。
I can't believe you hit Derek.
我不敢相信你打了德裡克。
I know. Did you see
the expression on his face?
我知道。你看見他當時臉上的表情了嗎？
-That was cool.
-Listen.
－那太酷了。
－聽著。
I know that we started out as foe.
我知道開始的時候我們是敵人。
But after that courageous act...
但在那勇敢的一擊後...
...that you showed me
against the one they call Derek...
...你向我表明了你也反對那個叫德裡克的人...
...maybe someday
we could become friends.
...也許有一天我們會變成朋友。
Friends who ride majestic,
translucent steeds...
騎著高頭駿馬...
...shooting flaming arrows
across the Bridge of Hemdale.
...射著燃燒的箭跨過漢姆戴爾大橋的朋友。
I would follow you into the mists
of Avalon, if that's what you mean.
假如那樣的話，我就追隨你進入
「仙女島」的迷霧。
Do you wanna see something cool
that only three people have seen?
你要不要看個很酷的東西？只有三個人見過。
Okay, open your eyes.
好，睜開眼睛。
See that black smudge
right there on the blade?
看到刀刃上的污跡了嗎？
-Yeah.
-Look at it closely.
－看見了。
－仔細看看。
-Pretty recognizable signature.
-No.
－清晰可辨的簽名。
－看不出。
Randy Jackson from American Idol.
《美國偶像》的蘭迪-傑克遜。
Why do you have Randy Jackson's
autograph on a martial-arts weapon?
你為什麼讓蘭迪-傑克遜親筆簽名在一件武術兵器上呢？
I bumped into him
and all I had was this sword...
我碰到他，當時我手裡只有這把劍...
...and you're not gonna not get
Randy Jackson's autograph.
...並且你不可能不要蘭迪-傑克遜的簽名的。
I would've done
the exact same thing.
我就不會那樣做。
Now, do you wanna see
something really cool?
現在，你想不想看看真正酷的東西？
-Of course.
-Turn off the lights.
－當然。
－把燈關掉。
Industrial-strength
night-vision goggles.
優質夜視鏡。
Holy Santa Claus shit.
哇塞，天哪。
Can you imagine if we had these
when we were 1 2?
假如我們12歲就有這些東西的話，
你能想像嗎？
Even better.
We got them when we're 40.
現在更酷。我們40歲擁有了這些。
You know what's amazing? They're
not that noticeable on your face.
你知道什麼最令人吃驚嗎？
戴在臉上沒那麼顯眼。
-Right?
-Yeah.
－是嗎？
－是的。
I can't believe I've been living here
for two weeks...
我無法相信我在這裡已經住了兩個星期了...
...and I'm walking
around this place...
...我漫步在這個地方...
...thinking I've got a huge doucher
for a stepbrother.
...認為我認了一個大傻瓜做為異父異母的兄弟。
Secretly, you're not a doucher.
私下來講，你並不是一個大傻瓜。
Let's play a game, all right?
讓我們玩個遊戲，怎麼樣？
On the count of three,
name your favorite dinosaur.
數三下，說出最喜歡的恐龍。
Don't even think about it, just name it.
Ready? One, two, three.
不要想，直接說。
準備好了嗎？一，二，三。
-Velociraptor.
－速龍。
Favorite non-pornographic magazine
to masturbate to.
用其手淫的最喜歡的非色情雜誌。
-Good Housekeeping.
－時尚好管家。
If you were a chick, who's
the one guy you'd sleep with?
假如你是個小妞，你最想與哪個男性睡覺？
-John Stamos.
－約翰·斯塔莫斯。
-What?
-Did we just become best friends?
－怎麼回事？
－我們不是剛剛才變成好朋友的嗎？
Yep.
是的。
Do you wanna go do karate
in the garage?
你想在車庫裡玩空手道嗎？
Yup!
是的！
-Yeah!
－耶！
I think they're starting to
like each other.
我想他們開始喜歡彼此了。
I got a really bad feeling about this.
我有種不詳的感覺。
-Sword fight!
-I know.
－鬥劍！
－我知道。
Sword fight!
鬥劍！
-Exactly the same!
-I know! That's so weird.
－一摸一樣！
－我知道，這太奇怪了。
Now you're in trouble.
現在你有麻煩了。
-Come on!
-No!
－加油！
－不！
They're betting against you,
but you can do it!
他們打賭你會輸，但你能行的。
-Yeah!
－耶！
Is this a bad time?
時間不對？
What the hell's going on?
到底怎麼回事？
Ma, Mr. Doback, okay,
Dale and I were just--
媽媽，多巴克先生，嗯，戴爾和我只是---
Please, stop calling me Mr. Doback.
請別再叫我多巴克先生了。
Sorry. Okay.
抱歉。好的。
Mom, Doback...
媽媽，多巴克...
...we think it would be very prudent--
...我們在想那是否很划算---
-Can we turn our beds into bunk beds?
-Yes.
－我們能不能把我們的床改裝成雙層床？
－是的。
Why are you guys so sweaty?
你們倆怎麼大汗淋漓的？
We've already figured out how.
The beds match up perfectly.
我們已經算好了怎麼樣把兩張床完美的結合在一起。
It would give us so much extra space
in our room to do activities.
那樣就會留出更多的空間來活動。
Please say yes.
請答應我們吧。
You don't need our permission
to build bunk beds.
你們沒有必要徵求我們的同意。
You're adults.
You can do what you want.
你們是成年人了。可以做你們想做的事。
So...?
那麼...?
I'm not making myself clear.
我沒有表達清楚。
I don't give a fuck.
我不反對。
Now, you both have
several interviews tomorrow.
現在，你們兩個明天有幾個面試。
I would think you'd be focused
on that and not building bunk beds.
我想你們應該把注意力放到那上面，
而不是建造雙層床上。
-So...?
－那...?
-We can? No?
-Yes. Yes, you can make bunk beds.
－我們可以？不？
－可以，可以，你們可以造雙層床。
-I knew it.
-Okay. You are not gonna regret this.
－我早就知道。
－好。你們不會後悔的。
We'll get so much more
activities done.
我們有那麼多的活動要做。
This is the funnest night ever!
這是最最有趣的晚上！
This is so scary.
太讓人害怕了。
-How you doing over there?
-Really good.
－那邊怎麼樣？
－非常好。
Okay.
好。
Does your son know anything
about carpentry?
你兒子會木工嗎？
No, not a th-- Did I hear a drill?
不，一點都---我聽見電鑽了？
-Dale! Dale, no power tools!
-Power tools.
－戴爾！戴爾，不准使用電動工具！
－不准使用電動工具。
-What?
-No power tools!
－什麼？
－不准使用電動工具！
-No, I forgot, I have to brush my teeth.
-That is not your toothbrush.
－沒有，我剛才忘了我要刷牙了。
－那不是你的牙刷。
Oh, okay. Well, I'm all done anyway.
哦，好的。好了，馬上就好了。
-We did it.
-We did it!
－我們成功了！
It looks amazing!
看起來太神了！
Look at that! That looks like
what you'd buy from a store!
看看這！就像從商店裡買的一樣！
-Should've been a bunk bed all along.
-Look at this space.
－早就應該有個雙層床。
－看看這空間。
-We could do aerobics in here.
-So many activities!
－我們可以在這裡做有氧健美操。
－很多很多活動！
-Do step class.
-It's making my head spin...
－做踏板操。
－想能做多少活動...
-...how many activities we can do.
-Play Army men.
－...想得我頭昏腦脹。
－玩玩具軍人。
-Yeah.
-Come on.
－是的。
－來吧。
Hey, I never asked you.
Do you like guacamole?
嘿，我還沒問過你。
你喜歡色拉調味醬嗎？
Oh, Brennan! Oh, God!
哦，布倫南！哦，天哪!
Brennan! Brennan!
布倫南！布倫南！
Dad. Nancy. It's bad.
爸爸，南希，不好了。
It's so bad.
There's blood everywhere.
不好了。
到處都是血。
The bunk beds were a terrible idea.
Why'd you let us do that?
建雙層床這個想法太糟糕了。
你們為什麼同意我們去做那？
It's so bad!
太糟了！
How would you describe that?
你感覺怎麼樣？
-It's not so bad.
-Right. See?
－不算太糟。
－好。看到了吧？
Put your beds back.
把你們的床放回原位。
Rumpus time is over.
騷亂時間結束。
You got a big day tomorrow.
You need your eight hours.
明天是很重要的一天。
你們需要8個小時的休息。
And although she was 88 years old,
she never stopped believing.
儘管她都88歲了，她從來沒有停止過信仰。
And although she was 88 years old,
she never stopped believing.
儘管她都88歲了，她從來沒有停止過信仰。
It's 8: 20 in the a.m.
現在是上午8：20。
Coming up next, a recent study
by the American Council....
接下來，是美國議會最近的一個研究...
Look at her. She's hot.
看看她。真熱辣。
Okay, guys, this is it.
Good luck. Don't be late.
好了，夥計們，都在這裡了。
祝你們好運。別遲到了。
Dad, I need to borrow
some clothes for the interview...
爸，我需要借些面試穿的衣服...
...since I don't have
any fancy clothes.
...我根本就沒什麼體面衣服。
You go in my closet, take whatever
you need. You guys gotta look sharp.
你可以去我的衣櫥，看看你需要什麼。
你也一樣，布倫南。你們要看起來機敏點。
This is the most important
day of our lives.
這是我們生活中最重要的一天。
-Okay.
-No pressure, no pressure.
－好了。
－別有壓力，別有壓力。
-All right? Relax.
-Okay.
－好嗎？放鬆。
－好的。
I gotta go. I gotta go.
我要走了。我要走了。
This is your day.
Remember that. You own it.
這是你們的日子。
記住。這一天是你們的。
-This is your one day!
-All right.
－這是你們的日子！
－好的。
Mr. Huff, Mr. Jeener
is ready for your interview.
哈夫先生， 金格爾先生已經準備好了你們的面試。
Actually, we'll be
interviewing as a team.
實際上，我們將一起面試。
We're here to fuck shit up.
我們去把場子攪了。
Move it!
閃開！
Hey!
嘿！
Well, Brennan, you certainly
have had a lot of jobs.
嗯，布倫南，你做過很多工作。
I'm a bit of a spark plug.
我有點像個插頭。
And, Human Resources lady,
when I think--
並且，人力資源夫人，當我想---
-You know, it's-- Actually, it's Pam.
-I'm sorry.
－你知道，其實，我叫帕姆。
－抱歉。
-Well, Pan....
-No, my name is Pam.
－嗯，潘...
－不，我叫帕姆。
-Are you saying Pan or Pam?
-I'm saying Pam.
－你說的是潘還是帕姆？
－我說的是帕姆。
Yeah, I'm sorry, who is this
gentleman sitting behind you?
好了，我很抱歉，坐在你後面的那位男士是誰？
Hello, Ms. Lady. I'm Dale.
I'm Brennan's stepbrother...
你好，夫人。我是戴爾。布倫南的異父兄弟...
...and I think I might be able to help
with the Pan-Pam dilemma.
...我想我能幫助解決「潘還是帕姆」這個難題。
-Yeah, that'd be great.
-Pam.
－是的，那太棒了。
－帕姆。
-Pan.
-Pam.
－潘。
－帕姆。
-Pand. There's a D on the end.
-With an M.
－潘德。後面有個D。
－是個M。
-There's no D. It's Pam.
-It's like "comb," except P-A-N-M.
－沒有D。是帕姆。
－很像「comb」，不像是P-A-N-M。
-N-N. There's two N's.
-Two M's. That was the confusion.
－N-N。有兩個N。
－兩個M。這是讓人迷惑的。
No, there's just one M.
不，就一個M。
What do you say we interview you?
我們來面試你怎麼樣？
All right. Yes, that's a
sometimes-useful exercise.
好的。這有時是一個有用的練習。
Please put your hand down.
請把你的手放下來。
Go ahead.
開始吧。
How much money do you make
a year before taxes?
稅前你一年能掙多少錢？
Okay, I'm actually not comfortable
answering that.
嗯，這個問題我不好回答。
-Come on!
-We're doing the interview, not you.
－快點！
－我們現在是面試者，不是你。
Here's a shot out of a cannon:
Oprah, Barbara Walters, your wife.
在一個佳能相機裡有一個鏡頭：
歐普拉，芭芭拉.沃爾特斯,你妻子
You gotta fuck one,
marry one, kill one. Go!
你必須要干一個，娶一個，殺一個。開始！
I think we're done here. Thank you.
我想我們就到這兒吧。謝謝。
Mr. Huff, under your references,
you listed Dale Doback...
哈夫先生，在你資料下面，你列出了戴爾.多巴克...
...which I know is this gentleman,
but you also listed...
...我知道這是位男士，但是你還列出了...
-..."Jesus Christ, our Lord and Savior."
-Yeah.
－...「耶穌基督，我們的神和救世主。」
－是的。
Yeah, we are looking for people
we can contact.
好，我們現在正招我們能聯繫到的人。
We wanna tell you the stuff
we're not good at.
我們想告訴你我們不擅長的事情。
-Our weaknesses.
-So we're clear up front.
－我們的缺點。
－我們事先說清楚。
-Okay.
-We're not generally comfortable...
－好吧。
－總得來講，我們不習慣...
-...in an office setting, I would say.
-I get cooped up.
－...辦公室環境。
－我覺得很壓抑。
I won't go into an office
that's ever been used before.
我不會進以前用過的辦公室。
I am no good before 1 1 a.m.
我上午11點前狀態不好。
I also get headaches from computers,
so I can't be around them too long.
電腦會讓我頭疼，
所以我不能在電腦周圍呆的時間太長了。
I take stuff.
我吸毒。
I need someone to go up and down
with me in the elevator.
我需要有人陪我在電梯裡上下。
I have a weakness for sweets.
我偏愛糖果。
Other weaknesses?
還有其它的缺點嗎？
We're slow learners and we're
not particularly good listeners.
我們學的很慢，並且特別不喜歡聽別人講。
-That'll be a huge problem.
-We're also slow learners.
－這是個大問題。
－這方面，我們學的也很慢。
First of all,
I needed someone to work--
首先，我需要一個人去做---
Wait, shut your mouth.
Shut your mouth.
等一下，閉嘴。閉上你的嘴。
I think we've had enough--
我想已經夠了---
-Shush up for one second.
-Shut your mouth.
－閉一會嘴！
－閉上你的嘴.
-Wait, shut your mouth.
-I'm sorry, what did you just say?
－等一下，閉上你的嘴。
－對不起，你剛才說什麼？
-You're just coming off stupid.
-I'm coming off stupid?
－你表現的很蠢。
－我表現的很蠢？
You're wearing tuxedos to a job that
requires you to clean bathrooms.
你穿著燕尾服來應聘一個打掃廁所的工作。
-Please leave this office, we're done.
-Do we get any sort of souvenir?
－請離開辦公室，已經結束了。
－我們有沒有什麼紀念品？
Get out of my office!
滾出我的辦公室！
I'm looking to hire guys I don't mind
hanging out with for 1 2 hours a day.
我願意一天花12個小時出去找可雇的人。
You guys seem like cool guys.
你們看起來很酷。
Got hair similar to mine,
you wear tuxedos to the interview.
與我相似的頭髮，穿著燕尾服來面試。
That's funny, it's ironic. I get that.
很滑稽，也很有諷刺性。我能理解。
Underplaying the whole formality of it.
I think that's funny as hell.
把整個事情不要弄得太過火。
我認為這太有趣了。
So let's do this, you know?
You guys are hired. You're in.
讓我們一起幹吧，你知道嗎？
你們被僱傭了。
Unless you're the weirdest guys ever
and I don't see it.
除非你們是最古怪的人，而且我不這麼認為。
Great.
太棒了。
-Was that a fart?
-I don't know.
－你放屁了？
－我不知道。
I can taste it.
我能嘗出來。
On my tongue.
用我的舌頭。
Okay, I'll be honest with you.
I did fart.
好吧，我必須要對你誠實。
我確實放屁了。
Is that onion? Onion and--
Onion and ketchup.
洋蔥嗎？洋蔥和---
洋蔥和番茄醬 。
-lt stinks. And this is a small room.
-Shit.
－很臭。這是一個小房間。
－該死。
Okay, now the tuxedos
seem kind of fucked up.
好，現在燕尾服好像被糟蹋了。
God. We were so close.
天。我們幾乎都要成功了。
So, what do we do for jobs?
Is your dad really gonna kick us out?
那，關於工作我們怎麼辦？
你爸爸真的要把我們踢出去嗎？
Listen, don't worry about my dad.
聽著，不用擔心我爸爸。
Got him sewn up.
我們使他心力憔悴。
We've gotta start thinking bigger,
though, Brennan.
但是我們已經找到出發點了，布倫南。
Listen, what are you really good at?
聽著，你真正擅長什麼？
Singing. I'm a world-class singer.
歌唱。我是世界級的歌手。
See? Right there,
that's an amazing skill.
是嗎？非常好，那是一項了不起的技能。
Now, what am I good at?
現在，我擅長什麼呢？
I can shred on the drums
and I'm a marketing wiz.
我鼓敲的比較棒，並且我是個市場奇才。
Put all that together,
what do you get?
把這合到一塊，你能想到什麼？
-I don't know, a band?
-No, that's been done before.
－我不知道，一個樂隊？
－不，那是以前幹的。
Even better: we are gonna start an
international entertainment company.
有更好的：我們要開一家國際娛樂公司。
The biggest and the best.
最大的並且是最好的。
And we're gonna call it
Prestige Worldwide.
我們就叫它「環球聲譽」。
That sounds so cool.
聽起來很酷。
I feel like a lightning bolt
hit the tip of my penis.
我感覺豁然開朗。
Yeah. Yeah.
對。對。
We're brothers. This is why we met.
我們是兄弟。這注定了我們要相遇。
-To form this alliance, right?
-Right?
－組成一個聯盟，對嗎？
－對啊？
That's why our parents met,
so this idea could happen.
這也是我們爸媽相遇的原因，所以才有了這個創意。
-Okay, what do we do?
-We get to work.
－好了，我們現在要做什麼？
－我們要動工了。
And we hit the beat laboratory
right now. Let's go.
我們要馬上去練鼓房。我們走。
-What?
-Wait.
－怎麼了？
－等等。
What time is it?
幾點？
-4:30.
4:32.
-I can't go down Whitworth right now.
-Okay.
－我不能現在走惠特沃思路。
－好吧。
We should go this way.
我們應該走這條路。
-What's up?
-Chris Gardocki.
－怎麼回事？
－可裡斯.卡爾多吉。
-What?
-He gets in my face...
－什麼？
－他很凶...
...and I just don't wanna
deal with the hassle now.
...我現在不想惹這個麻煩。
-Are you this scared?
-Can we please go the long way?
－你如此害怕？
－我們難道不能繞遠路嗎？
-Down Cutler?
-Yeah.
－走卡特勒街？
－是的。
But that's 45 minutes.
但那要走45分鐘。
You're gonna shame me
into doing this.
你讓我覺得這樣做很丟人。
-You sound stupid.
-You'll be sorry. Okay, I'm stupid.
－你聽起來太可笑了。
－你會後悔的。好吧，我很可笑。
Oh, man.
哦，老兄。
Oh, God, there they are.
哦，天哪，他們在那。
Oh, my God, is that Dale Doback?
哦，上帝，那不是戴爾.多巴克嗎？
-Let's make him lick dog shit.
-Yeah.
－我們要讓他舔狗屎。
－是的。
Hey, fag-stick. Long time, no see.
嘿，同性戀雞巴。很久不見了。
Is that your boyfriend?
Is that your butt buddy?
那是你男朋友嗎？
那就是你的狗屁朋友嗎？
Look, Mr. Gardocki,
just leave me alone, will you?
聽著，卡爾多吉先生，別煩我，可以嗎？
Shut your mouth, ese.
閉上你的臭嘴。
You guys just go back and have fun
on your jungle gym, okay?
回到你們的地盤去玩，好嗎？
Does butt buddy have a name?
你那狗屁朋友有名字嗎？
If you're referring to me as
butt buddy, yes, I do have a name.
如果你說的狗屁朋友是我的話，是的
我有名字。
It's Brennan Huff.
布倫南.哈夫
If you don't come over here
and lick that white dog shit...
假如你不過來舔那白色的狗屎的話...
...I'm gonna plow into your nose
with my fist.
...我就用我的拳頭打破你的鼻子。
-I'm not licking any white dog shit.
-I'll lick the shit if you leave us alone.
－我不會去舔那白色狗屎。
－假如你們離我們遠點我就去舔那屎。
Dale, you're not licking
dog shit, okay? They're kids.
戴爾，你不會去舔的，對嗎？
他們只是孩子。
-Brennan, it's just dog shit.
-It's ridiculous!
－布倫南，那只是狗屎。
－這太荒唐了！
-Hello, how are--?
-Oh, God!
－嗨，你好---?
－哦，天哪！
Leave him alone! Leave him alone!
放開他！放開他！
Get them!
抓住他們！
So maybe you don't
go down that way anymore.
也許你們再也不會走那條路了。
Maybe you go the long way home.
也許你們繞遠道回家。
That's what we talked about.
We'll take the long way home.
我們就是這麼說的。
我們會繞遠道回家。
You know in that one scene
in The Wizard of Oz...
你知道《綠野仙蹤》裡有一幕...
...when the flying monkeys
pull apart the Scarecrow?
...飛猴把稻草人扯成了碎片？
That's what it was like.
就像當時的情況一樣。
-It's okay, it's okay.
-I'm so sorry.
－沒事了，沒事了。
－我很難過。
Is my dad mad about
the stuff that happened?
爸爸對發生的事情是不是很生氣？
Robert was very upset, yes.
是的，羅伯特非常生氣。
He knows that you interviewed
as a team.
他知道你們一起去面試了。
And he heard about the fart.
他還聽說了那個屁。
-Oh, he did?
-Yeah.
－哦，真的嗎？
－是的。
You just couldn't hold it, or you--?
你不能撐著，或者你們---?
-No. I thought it was gonna be silent.
-lt was not silent.
－不。我想不會放出聲的。
－它有聲音。
Just kept going, and it made a sound.
It was embarrassing.
放著放著就出聲了。
那很令人尷尬。
It got louder.
越來越響。
So listen, Bobby,
I'll get those keys made tomorrow...
聽著，巴比。我明天會把這些鑰匙配出來...
-...and then we'll start setting up times.
-Thank you.
－...然後我們就可以開始計劃時間了。
－謝謝你。
-Hi, Mom.
-Hi.
－嗨，媽媽。
－嗨。
-Okay, bye.
-Bye.
－好了，拜拜。
－拜拜。
-Always nice to see you.
-You too.
－見到你總是很高興。
－我也是。
Hey, guys.
嘿，夥計們。
Looks like your
free ride's over, huh?
看起來你們免費住房的時光結束了，嗯？
Have fun living on the streets.
祝你們大街上住的愉快。
Okay, cool. Good chatting, you guys.
Bye, Mom.
好吧，酷。聊得很開心，夥計們。
再見，媽媽。
-Bye.
-See you, buddy.
－再見。
－回見，老兄。
What was he doing here?
他來幹什麼？
We're putting the house
on the market.
我們要賣掉房子。
-Where are we moving?
-ls the house haunted?
－我們搬到哪兒？
－房子鬧鬼了嗎？
Nancy and I are retiring...
我和南希要退休了...
...and sailing around the world
on my boat.
...我們要開船航游世界。
We are living the dream.
我們馬上就要實現我們的夢想了。
Well, what about us?
那，我們呢？
I'm sorry. Robert-- We thought that...
抱歉。羅伯特---我們認為...
...you should take responsibility
for your own lives.
...你們應該對自己的生活負責。
This is the exciting part:
We're going to put enough
money in your accounts...
我們會給你們的賬戶上足夠的錢...
...for a security deposit
on an apartment.
...做為你們租套公寓的押金。
What's this all about?
這到底怎麼回事？
More than just money, we're gonna get
you another kind of support as well.
除了錢，我們還將給你們別的資助。
You're both gonna see therapists.
Nancy thinks it'll help.
你們倆去看心理醫生，
南希認為會對你們有所幫助。
-Guys, that's nonnegotiable.
-Hold on. We're not going on the boat...
－孩子們，沒得商量。
－等等，我們不和你們一起去...
...Derek's selling the house,
we have to go to therapy?
...德裡克要賣掉房子，
我們必須去看醫生？
-What the fuck happened?
-Hey!
－這都他媽的什麼事啊？
－嘿！
Look, I know this seems
really, really sudden...
聽著，我知道這真的很突然...
...and just sort of unfair
and cruel and--
...並且有點不公平和殘酷--
-But it's nonnegotiable.
－但沒得商量。
I got a bellyful
of white dog crap in me...
我剛剛受夠了白狗屎...
...and now you lay this shit on me?
你現在又把狗屎拉我身上？
You're adults. It's time
you started acting like adults.
你們是成年人了。你們的行為就該像個成年人。
-Mom.
-I'm not backing down, Brennan.
－媽媽。
－我不會讓步的，布倫南。
Don't even try.
想都別想。
I know it seems hard,
but it's the best thing for both of you.
我知道這看起來很難，但對你們來說這再好不過了。
We do it because we love you.
我們這樣做是因為我們愛你們。
Dad, I'm doing this because
I love you: fuck you.
爸，我這樣做也是因為愛你：去你媽的...
-Anything else?
-No.
－還有別的問題嗎？
－沒有。
Bon voyage! Have a great time!
一路順風！旅途愉快！
Hey, what's up, Derek?
嘿，怎麼了，德裡克？
Yeah.
嗯
-Know what?
-Look what I got.
－你知道嗎？
－看我得到什麼了。
I'm sitting here thinking we finally got
a family together here...
我在想我們終於共同擁有了一個家庭...
...and now it's about to be taken away
because they think we're losers.
...現在他們認為我們不成器就要剝奪我們的生活。
-Because they don't understand us?
-Yeah.
－因為他們不理解我們？
－是。
They don't get that this lifestyle
is a choice.
他們不明白這是我們選擇的生活方式。
And all they think about
is that stupid boat.
他們只想著那艘破船。
I swear, I'm so pissed off
at my mom.
我發誓，我非常煩我媽。
As soon as she is of age,
I'm putting her in a home.
只要她老了我就把她一個人扔家裡。
We have got to get
Prestige Worldwide going.
我們必須著手我們的「環球聲譽」了。
It's the thing that's
gonna save this family.
這才是挽救這個家的方法、
I was thinking we should
have a investor presentation...
我想我們應該做一個有關投資的陳述...
...Iike on The Apprentice.
...就像《學徒》上一樣。
We gotta start
with some capital somewhere.
我們從某些投資機構獲得一些啟動資金。
Here's the thing, though:
但關鍵是：
If we're gonna start
a huge multinational corporation...
如果我們準備開一家大型跨國公司...
...I have to hear you sing.
...那我不得不聽聽你的歌。
Can't you just trust that
I'm a really, really good singer?
你不相信我是一個真正的好歌手嗎？
Just one song, so I know
what your voice sounds like.
就一首歌，我就會知道你的音質怎麼樣。
Yeah, yeah. I'll just do it.
好，好。那我唱好了。
No big deal. I'll just dive into it
and just start singing.
沒什麼大不了的。那我將投入地唱一次。
Jesus, my heart is beating
so fast right now.
天哪，我的心現在跳得好快。
Okay, just do it. Just do it.
行，唱。唱。
Just--
馬上---
You know, I don't know.
你知道，我
I didn't sing too loud, because I don't
wanna wake up Robert and Nancy.
我沒唱那麼大聲，因為我不想吵醒羅伯特和南希。
My throat's sore. I've had
a sore throat for a month and a half.
我嗓子啞了。已經啞了一個半月了。
And this is not an acoustic
environment that's suitable...
而且這個聲樂環境不適合...
...to request this from me.
...要求我做這些。
You gotta know,
I'm not just some guy.
你知道，我不是那些不懂音樂的人。
Brennan, that is
the voice of an angel.
布倫南，那簡直是天使的聲音。
Brennan, I can't even make
eye contact with you right now.
布倫南，我現在甚至不敢看你了。
Your voice is like a combination
of Fergie and Jesus.
你的聲音好像結合了弗吉和上帝的特點。
Why can't you do that
in front of people?
你為什麼不在別人面前唱呢？
Are you messing with me right now?
你現在不是在耍我吧？
It's me, Dale.
是我，戴爾。
You're good.
你唱的很好。
-I know.
-This is gonna sound weird...
－我知道。
－這聽起來不可思議...
...but for a second, I think
you took on the shape of a unicorn.
但仔細看看，你剛才就像一個獨角獸一樣。
I felt like I was hovering
above my own body...
我感覺我在我自己的身體上方盤旋...
...watching myself sing.
...看著我自己在唱。
Now, let's move on
to other business.
現在，讓我們回到另一件事上。
First thing tomorrow, we gotta get
cracking on this investor presentation.
明天要做的第一件事就是解決投資陳述。
And guess what else.
This just came to me.
猜還有什麼事。這是我剛想到的。
-We're making a music video.
-Yeah!
－我們要製作一個音樂電視。
－沒錯!
What do we do about Derek
and the house?
我們怎麼處理德裡克和房子的事？
Don't worry about him.
不用擔心。
Oh, it's a great "nabe."
噢，這是一個好地段。
Frank Gifford
used to live down the block.
弗蘭克 吉弗德過去住在這街區。
-The Giff?
-Yeah, the Giff. Right down the block.
－吉弗德？
－是的，是他。他就在住這個街區。
I'm getting
a really good feeling about this.
我對這的感覺真的很好。
I am so glad.
很高興你們喜歡。
You get us that 1 0-year
interest-only loan, we got a deal.
按我們談好的，你給我們十年低息房貸。
Hey, fuckers!
Welcome to the neighborhood!
嘿，傻瓜們！
歡迎成為我們的鄰居！
-My name is Craig.
-The neighbor is a Nazi?
－我叫克雷格。
－鄰居是納粹分子？
You guys ever need fertilizer,
I've got a lot of it. Close to 80 tons.
你們這幫傢伙需要肥料麼，
我有很多，將近有80噸。
Hey, folks! How you doing?
You're gonna love this neighborhood.
嘿，夥計們！你們好？
你們會愛上這個地方的。
Every single house here recycles.
這裡的每棟房子都循環利用的。
-Okay, we're done here.
-Yeah, okay.
－好吧，今天就到這吧。
－好吧。
Hey, Derek, sprechen sie dick.
嘿，德裡克，你這個蠢貨。
Dale, I don't know how much
you know about therapy...
戴爾，我不知道你對心理治療瞭解多少...
...but it usually starts by you
telling me something about yourself.
...心理治療通常是從你給我講一些有關你的事情開始。
I work at a college as a janitor...
我在一個大學當清潔工...
...even though I'm smarter
than most of the people there.
...儘管我比那裡的大部分人都聰明。
Sometimes I see an equation
written on a blackboard...
有時我看到黑板上的一個等式...
...Iike half an equation,
and I'll just figure it out.
...哪怕半個等式，
我就能算出來。
-ls this Good Will Hunting?
-No.
－你說《心靈捕手》？
－不。
It sounds a lot like the plot
of Good Will Hunting.
聽起來很像《心靈捕手》的情節。
Yeah. Anyway.
My best friend is Ben Affleck....
是的。不管怎樣，我最好的朋友是本.艾弗雷克...
So I thought we'd begin
talking about your parents' divorce.
我認為我們要談談你父母的離婚。
Okay.
好吧。
How old were you
when they got divorced?
他們離婚的時候你多大？
-Fifteen.
-That's a hard age.
－15。
－一個多事的年齡。
-Yes. Yeah.
-Do you wanna talk...
－是的。是的。
－你想不想談一談...?
-...about some of those feelings?
-I love you.
－...當然的感覺？
－我愛你。
-Obviously, you don't know me.
-I love you so much.
－很顯然，你並不瞭解我。
－我非常愛你。
Thank you. And I will take that
as a feeling that you have...
謝謝。我會認為那是你在我這兒很自在...
...of comfortability with me.
...的一種感覺。
It's more than comfortability.
這不僅僅是自在。
-I mean, I fucking love you.
-Okay. I th--
－我的意思是，我真他媽的愛你。
－好。我認為---
I'm just thinking
about our life together.
我在想我們在一起的生活。
I feel like I'm walking on a cloud.
我感覺象走在雲端。
My penis is tingling right now.
我那兒開始興奮了。
-That is so off-putting.
-You're not feeling this?
－這讓人有點討厭。
－你沒這種感覺？
In no way, shape or form do I feel
any feelings of intimacy towards you...
一點都沒，我對你沒一丁點親近感...
...in any way whatsoever.
...無論從哪一方面來講。
You got a really dope
front lawn here.
這裡的房前草坪真的不錯。
You and your homeboys
can play on that.
你們和孩子們可以在上面玩耍。
-You can just say "lt looks good."
-Yeah.
－你只能說：「看起來還不錯了。」
－是的。
No, that's how I talk.
不，實事求是嘛。
Oh, you got a really fresh
entryway here. Pretty awesome.
噢，入門處空氣非常新鮮。真的很棒。
--show you the front of the house,
which is actual--
--領你們看看房子的前面部分，真的--
Will you vultures please give us some
privacy? He just died last night.
你們這些禿鷲就不能給我們點隱私嘛？
他昨天晚上剛剛去世。
What is going on here?
怎麼回事？
It was the asbestos in here,
that's what did it!
是這裡的石棉，石棉殺了他。
I've seen too many dead bodies.
我見過太多的死屍了。
-I can't be in here. I can't.
-No, no, no.
－我不能呆在這兒。我不能。
－不，不，不。
-Not bad.
-Eat shit, Derek.
－不壞啊。
－去吃屎吧，德裡克。
-Awesome B-day party, broheisens.
-You the man, Derek.
－很棒的生日晚會，兄弟們。
－你真行，德裡克。
Okay, who's this from? TJ?
好，這是誰送的？TJ？
Where are
the rest of my gifts, dude?
其它的禮物呢，老兄？
Totally joking around, TJ.
開玩笑的，TJ。
All right.
好。
Oh, yes! Yes! Callaway 3-wood.
噢，太棒了！太棒了！Callaway的3號木桿。
-Yeah!
－好！
Yeah.
好。
-Bomb it down the fairway, bitches!
-That's right.
－順著球道把球打飛，媽的。
－好。
Hi, my name is Jim.
Wanna suck my dick for money?
嗨，我是吉姆。
付你錢給我舔雞巴吧？
-It's just me. Hi.
-Oh, my God.
－是我，嗨。
－哦，我的天。
What are you doing?
This is the men's bathroom.
你在幹什麼？這是男廁所。
Happy anniversary.
紀念日快來。
-It's our second date.
-What?
－這是我們的第二次約會。
－什麼？
Listen, I'm sick of being
all coy and bashful, Dale. Okay?
聽著，我厭倦了那麼含蓄，戴爾，好嗎？
-We're in the bathroom.
-This'll just take a minute.
－這是廁所。
－那只要一分鐘。
There's really little you can
do about it. Let me just hop on.
你沒得選擇。讓我跳上來。
It's all slippery.
這太滑了。
Oh, my God!
噢，我的天哪！
It's getting tingly.
Something's gonna happen, Alice!
太刺激了。
我要射了，愛麗斯。
Oh, we just had sex.
哦，我們剛剛做愛了。
-Just the way I imagined it.
-I like you.
－以我想像的方式。
－我喜歡你。
I love you.
我愛你。
-Stay golden, Ponyboy. I gotta pee.
-Okay.
－樂吧，馬仔。我要尿尿了。
Oh, my God.
哦，天哪。
You're incredible.
你太不可思議了。
Say hello to my little friend.
給我的小朋友問好。
-Just kidding. It's from Scarface.
-Scarface.
－開玩笑。《疤面煞星》上的。
－《疤面煞星》
Shut the fuck up!
他媽的閉嘴！
-Sweet-ass gift, Teej.
-Yeah, not bad.
－很酷的禮物，TJ。
－是的，不壞。
-I got it all mapped out.
-Okay.
－我都安排好了。
－好。
-I'm following your lead, though.
-I'll get all eyes on us.
－但是，我聽你的。
－我會讓他們都注意我們的。
-Okay.
-Just like we planned.
－好。
－就像我們計劃的那樣。
And then we'll drop the hammer.
然後我們一炮打響。
What were Dale and Brennan doing
with my video camera, do you know?
你知道戴爾和布倫南用我的攝像機忙什麼嗎？
I have no idea. And frankly,
I really don't care. So....
我不知道。坦白說，我真的不在乎。所以...
I would like to say a few things.
我想說幾句。
Derek, you are an outstanding
young man, son.
德裡克，你是一個非常出聲的年輕人，兒子。
And I would like say that
this is the image I have:
我想說：下面是我一直夢想的畫面：
That sometimes when I'm making love
to your mother and I realize that...
有時和你媽媽做愛時，我意識到...
...this is where you came from,
that I'm so moved...
...那就是你出生的地方，我就覺得激動...
...that I talked to my lawyer,
and not only are you going to be...
...我和我的律師談過，你不僅僅...
...in my heart forever, but you're
going to be in my will, young man.
...永遠在我心裡，並且也將會出現在我的遺囑中，年輕人。
-Okay. Okay.
-Okay?
－好了。好了。
－好了？
-Robert, that was fucking awesome.
-Thank you.
－羅伯特，那他媽的太棒了。
－謝謝。
You got a lot of this, buddy.
And you got a lot of these.
你得到了這麼多，夥計。
你得到了這麼多！
Thank you.
謝謝。
Everyone, if I could have
your attention, please.
各位，請注意。
For those of you
who don't know me...
有些人不認識我...
-...my name's Dale Doback.
-Check. Check.
－...我叫戴爾.多巴克。
－喂。喂。
I'm Robert's other son,
the biological one.
我是羅伯特的另一個兒子，親生兒子。
Check. Check.
喂。喂。
Probably wondering
why we gathered you here tonight...
你們可能奇怪為什麼我們把你們今天聚在這裡...
...besides Derek's birthday.
...撇開德裡克生日的原因。
We got a special surprise for you,
Derek, and everybody here--
我們有個特別的驚喜給你們，德裡克和這裡所有的人--
-Check, check.
-Check.
－喂，喂。
－喂。
-Dale. No, please.
-Don't interrupt them.
－戴爾，請別這樣。
－別打斷他們。
-I'm begging you.
-You wanna shut this down?
－求你了。
－要制止他們嗎？
-Just hold on.
-Derek, for your birthday...
－等一下。
－德裡克，為了你的生日...
...we thought we'd roll out...
....我想我們要開始...
...a once-in-a-lifetime
business opportunity.
...一生只有一次的創業。
Happy birthday, Derek.
德裡克，生日快樂。
Music.
音樂。
Prestige Worldwide,
wide, wide, wide.
"環球聲譽",譽，譽，譽。
Prestige Worldwide.
環球聲譽
-The first word in entertainment.
-First word.
－娛樂開篇語。
－開篇語。
-Management.
-Financial portfolios.
－管理。
－金融投資組合。
-lnsurance.
-Computers.
－保險。
－電腦。
-Black leather gloves.
-Research and development.
－黑皮手套。
－研究和發展。
Putting in the man-hours to study
the science of what you need.
花費工時來研究你所需要的科學。
Last week we put Liquid Paper
on a bee...
上個星期我們把塗改液塗到了蜜蜂上...
...and it died.
...蜜蜂死了。
-Security.
－安全。
-And--
-And.
－還有--
－還有。
投資者？
-Possibly you.
－可能就是你。
-Oh, this is classic. This is--
-We'd like to present...
－哦，這真經典。這--
－我們要呈現...
...the world premiere of Prestige
Worldwide's first music video...
...環球聲譽的首張音樂視頻的首次公演...
...by our first act, Huff and Doback.
...由我們首次製作，哈夫和多巴克。
-Roll it.
－播放。
Pay close attention, Dad.
It's gonna look familiar.
爸，仔細看。
你會看著很眼熟的。
-This is-- This is perfect.
-ls that my boat?
－這--這太棒了。
－那是我的船？
Yes, it is.
是的。
What are you doing on my boat?
你們在我的船上幹什麼？
（歌詞：）The Nina, the Pinta
The Santa Mariia
I'll do you in the bottom
While you're drinking sangria
Nachos and Lemonheads
On my dad's boat
You won't go down
'Cause my dick can float
We sail around the world
And go port to port
Every time I come
I produce a quart
That is offensive. Brennan, Dale.
太無禮了。布倫南，戴爾。
I gotta have me my boats and ho's
Deadliest Catch without the crabs
We're almost out of gas
Call the Arabs
Pull up the anchor
'Cause we're leaving dry land
Get below deck
With a dick in your hand
Boats and ho's
I gotta have me my boats and ho's
Are you ready for some
world-class vocalization?
-Get a partner.
-Wait a minute.
－找個合作夥伴。
－等一下。
-Who's steering the boat?
-Dad, please shut up.
－誰在開船？
－爸，請閉嘴。
Please shut up!
請閉嘴!
Yeah!
酷！
So...
嗯...
...big question is:
...問題是：
Aside from the damage to the boat,
which we will fix...
除了船的損壞，我們還要修補哪個...
...what'd you think
of the presentation?
...你們認為我們的陳述如何？
Brennan, I think that what you did
to Robert's boat was horrid.
布倫南，我認為你們對羅伯特的船的
所作所為太糟了。
Having said that,
I think that both of you boys...
除了那個，我認為你們倆...
...showed a lot of enthusiasm
and inventiveness.
...表現出了極大的熱情和創造性。
Yes. Thank you.
是的。謝謝。
You gotta be kidding me.
你在開玩笑。
They destroyed our dream
and you're calling it inventive.
他們粉碎了我們的夢想，而你卻稱其創造性。
-No, no, no. I didn't mean it like that.
-Yes, you did.
－不，不，不。我不是那個意思。
－是的，你就是那個意思。
Come on, you did.
算了吧，你就是那個意思。
It's gonna be four years, at least,
before we can sail anywhere.
至少還要等四年，我們才能開始航行。
-And you could care less, admit it.
-I will not admit that...
－你並不是很在乎，承認吧。
－我不會承認...
-...because it is not true.
-Oh, yeah.
－...因為那不是真的。
－哦。是。
But, you know,
I do think that you could show...
但是，你知道，我認為你可以表現出...
...a little bit more attentiveness
to your son and your stepson...
...對你的兒子和繼子更多點的關注...
...who obviously need you.
...他們很明顯需要你。
It's true, Dr. Doback.
是真的，多巴克先生。
You've been very cold
and unsupportive of our dreams.
你一直都我們的夢想漠不關心，也不支持。
You wrecked my fucking boat,
you goon!
你毀了我的船！
你個流氓！
Don't speak to my son like that.
別那樣對我的兒子說話。
Your son's costing me $80,000.
你的兒子讓我損失了8萬美元。
We could bicker about this all night,
but what's done is done, Dad.
我們可以整晚都爭吵這件事情，
但是爸，發生的已經發生了。
-Are you guys gonna invest or not?
-That's it! That's it!
－你投資還是不投資？
－對！對！
-What are you doing?
-Grab the wheel!
－你在幹什麼？
－抓住方向盤！
I can't believe
you're being so stingy.
我無法相信你現在這麼小氣。
-Robert, come down.
-It's a simple business decision.
－羅伯特，下來。
－那是一個非常簡單的生意決策。
You jackaloons!
混蛋！
You're failures! Failures!
你們是失敗者！失敗者！
And you're embarrassing yourself,
you geriatric fuck!
你是在使自己難堪，你個老頭！
-Brennan.
-Two things:
－布倫南。
－兩件事情：
You keep your liver-spotted hands
off my beautiful mother.
你把你張滿豬肝色斑點的手從我母親身上拿開。
She's a saint!
她是個聖徒！
Then you sit down and you write Dale
and Brennan a check for $1 0,000.
然後坐下來給戴爾和布倫南簽張1萬美元的支票。
Oh, stop it.
哦，閉嘴。
Or I'm gonna shove one of those fake
hearing devices so far up your ass...
否則我會把你那冒牌助聽器塞到你的屁股裡...
-Brennan!
-...you can hear the sound...
－布倫南！
－...這樣你就能到聽到...
...of your small intestine
as it produces shit!
...腸子產生糞便的聲音！
-All right, here we go.
-Oh, my Lord.
－好，我們可以開始了。
－哦，我的上帝。
Somebody should've done this
a long time ago, and I'm gonna do it.
有人應該早這樣做了，現在我來做。
-What are you doing?
-Robert.
－你幹什麼？
－羅伯特。
There are consequences
for your actions.
這就是你行為的後果。
-No! Robert!
-Dad!
－不！羅伯特！
－爸！
-This is not the answer.
-You're next, mister.
－這不是答案。
－你下一個，小子。
-You understand me?
-Yes.
－明白我的話了嗎？
－明白。
-Certain behaviors...
-Let go of me.
－某些行為...
－放開我。
-...will not be tolerated!
-My ass is on fire!
－不能被容忍！
－我的屁股很疼！
Wow, the tree looks great, Nancy.
Really tasteful.
哇，聖誕樹看起來很漂亮，南希。
很有品味。
Thank you, Dale. That's a very nice
sweater you're wearing.
謝謝，戴爾。你穿的毛衣很不錯。
It was my mom's.
I took the shoulder pads out.
是我媽媽的。
我把墊肩拿掉了。
Oh, and, Brennan? Denise called...
哦，布倫南？戴妮絲打電話...
...and she said she can't go out
with you on New Year's Eve...
...說她不能在除夕和你出去了...
...because she's not your girlfriend,
she's your therapist.
...因為她不是你女朋友，她是你的心理師
-ls that what she said?
-Yeah.
－她那樣說的？
－是的。
She's a rascal.
她真是個小壞蛋。
Hey, Dad, Nancy?
嘿，爸，南希？
Would it be cool if Brennan and l
opened just one present each...
假如我和布倫南在聖誕夜每人只打開一件禮物...
...since it's Christmas Eve?
...會不會很酷？
I'm gonna go down to the
Cheesecake Factory, have a drink.
我要去起司蛋糕店喝一杯。
But it's Christmas Eve.
但這是聖誕夜。
Merry Christmas.
聖誕快樂。
-Yes.
-Yeah.
－好。
I had my eye on one.
我一直盯著這個呢。
I hope it's what I think it is.
我希望這是我想要的。
Oh, my God. Hulk Hands!
哦，我的天，綠巨人手套！
Wait, Dale got Hulk Hands?
等下，戴爾得到了綠巨人手套？
Well, you reek of Scotch
and cheesecake.
哦，你渾身都是威士忌和起司蛋糕的味道。
You know...
你知道...
...tonight at the Cheesecake Factory
was the happiest I've been in months.
...今天晚上在起司店是我幾個月來最高興的一天。
-Well, then I feel very sorry for you.
-Well, just....
－嗯，我為你感到很難過。
－嗯，只是...
Nancy, I don't know if I can ever
forgive them for wrecking my boat.
南希，我不知道我是否可以原諒他們毀了我的船。
-Why are you giving up?
-I'm not giving up. I'm not.
－你為什麼要放棄？
－我沒有放棄。我沒有。
-You are. You're giving up on our boys.
-But they're 40.
－你放棄了。你放棄了我們的孩子。
－但他們已經40了。
I don't care how old they are.
They're still our children.
我不在乎他們多大了。他們終究還是我們的孩子。
Well, sometime it's got to matter
how old they are.
嗯，有時要在乎他們多大了。
That's all we do, is--
Oh, sweet Jesus.
那是我們要做的，是--
哦，天呢。
Oh, it--
You know, they'll go back to bed.
哦，那--
你知道，他們會回去睡覺的。
See? They're sleepwalking.
看到了吧？他們在夢遊。
No. No.
不。不。
See, back to bed.
看，回去睡覺了。
They'll be fine.
他們會好起來的。
Just nonsense.
I'm gonna wake them up.
胡說。
我去把他們弄醒。
-No. Why would you do such a thing?
-Well, because it's--
－不。你為什麼要那樣做？
－好吧，因為那是--
-Never, ever wake up a sleepwalker.
-See, that's it.
－永遠，永遠不要叫醒夢遊者。
－看，夠了。
-We can't ever do anything.
-No.
－我們什麼都不能做。
－不。
But they could do real harm
to themselves or others.
但他們真的會傷害自己或別人。
-Oh, the Christmas presents.
-No, guys-- No, no, don't--
－哦，聖誕節禮物。
－不，孩子們--不，不，別--
-No. But--
-I think we should take control.
－不。但是--
－我想我們應該控制住。
-It's always about them.
-How do you propose to do that?
－總是他們的事。
－你打算怎樣去做？
-Oh, Jesus.
-Whatever you do, don't wake them.
－哦，天呢。
－什麼都醒，但別弄醒他們。
They might do real harm
to themselves or others.
他們真的可能會傷害自己或他人。
-Not everybody does know that.
-Oh, the Christmas tree!
－不是每一個人都知道這點。
－哦，聖誕樹！
Oh, not the-- No, don't--
All right, that's it!
哦，不要--不，別--
好了，夠了！
-I'm waking them up!
-No! No!
－ 我要把他們叫醒！
－不！不！
-Don't wake them up!
-That's a myth!
－別弄醒他們！
－那是謬論！
-Wake up, both of you.
-Don't.
－醒來，你們倆個。
－別。
I told you! I told you!
我告訴過你！我告訴過你！
Stop it! Don't hurt him!
住手！別傷害他！
The pictures! Nancy!
拍下來！南希！
Robert!
羅伯特！
I mean, I was driving around
with a buddy of mine, Topher.
我是說，我當時和我的一個哥們，托弗，兜風。
You guys remember Topher, right?
你們記得托弗，對嗎？
Driving around, he has this
brand-new Testarossa, right?
他開著嶄新的法拉利，嗯？
We hit this four-point buck. Dead.
Lying in the road.
我們撞上了只雄鹿。死了。
就躺在路上。
Long story short,
we sue the state of Michigan.
長話短說，我們起訴了密歇根州。
I end up getting 1 25 G's. Okay?
You know what I spent that money on?
結果我得到了12.5萬美元的賠償。嗯？
你們知道我把錢花在什麼地方了嗎？
Sniper rifle to hunt deer.
獵鹿用的狙擊槍。
Either way, the deers lose,
my friends.
不管怎樣，鹿都輸了，我的朋友們。
Good riddance.
Eat all the damn flowers, anyway.
很好的解脫。
不管怎樣，把所有的該死的花都吃了。
If you'll excuse me...
很抱歉...
...I think I'm going to go into
the other room to check my hair.
...我想去另一個房間整理下我的頭髮。
-Excuse me.
-Sorry, everybody.
－抱歉。
－抱歉，各位。
If you'll excuse
my space-cadet wife here.
假如你們願意原諒我這個缺席的妻子。
Let's just say the meds
aren't helping.
我只能說偽君子一點都不樂於助人。
I'm kidding. Kidding. But not at all.
我開玩笑。開玩笑。一點都不。
I have to get some more gravy.
我去拿一些肉汁。
-Oh, Dale, it's right there.
-Oh, no.
－哦，戴爾。那兒有。
－哦，不。
Shush up, Nancy.
I have to get some more bread.
閉嘴，南希。我要去再拿一些麵包。
What did I do to deserve that?
我做什麼了值得他那樣？
What do any of us do
to deserve anything?
我們又做了什麼值得這一切？
I pay enough taxes to support
all these lazy goddamn liberals.
我付足夠的稅來支持這些懶惰的該死的自由黨人。
Get off me! Off!
Get back. Get back! Back!
閃開！閃開!退後。退後！退後！
-What do you want?
-Merry Christmas, darling.
－你想幹什麼？
－聖誕快來，親愛的。
-Merry Christmas.
-Oh, that was torture.
－聖誕快來。
－哦，那就是一種折磨。
I couldn't eat another bite of turkey
without thinking of you inside of me.
剛才在吃火雞的時候
我無時無刻不在想著你在我的體內。
Come on, let's try something illegal.
來，讓我們做件不合法的事情。
So, Tommy, what did you
get for Christmas?
湯米，聖誕節你得到了什麼禮物？
Well, Santa brought me the Bowflex
and $1 000 in fresh-minted $50 bills.
嗯，聖誕老人給我帶來了博飛啞鈴
和總值一千美元的嶄新的50美元鈔票。
Wanna know what I got
for Christmas? A crushed soul.
想知道聖誕節我得到了什麼嗎？
一個破碎的靈魂。
-Alice, please.
-Sing along, Santa.
－愛麗斯，求你了。
－一起唱，聖誕老人。
You know this song.
你知道這首歌的。
What is that noise?
什麼聲音？
It's-- This is the ghost.
這是--這是鬧鬼了。
-Just try to be quiet. Okay.
-You're right. You're right.
－小聲點。好吧。
－你是對的。你是對的。
-We've got to be discreet.
-All right.
－我們必須要謹慎。
－好的。
No, no! Oh, hey.
不，不！哦，嘿。
Are you all still talking in here?
你們還在這兒談話呢？
What are you doing?
你們在幹什麼？
Alice was moving a chair from the
living room into the dining room...
愛麗斯要把一把椅子從起居室搬到餐廳來...
...for an extra chair
and her back went out.
...多加一把椅子，但她的背脫臼了。
And I just did the best thing,
which is get right on the muscles...
我只是給她按摩下肌肉...
-Muscles.
-...so they don't seize up.
－肌肉。
－...他們沒有僵硬。
Just add some heat to it.
只是給肌肉添加點熱量。
Damn it, Dale, sit down.
該死，戴爾，坐下。
It's just a real deep, tight muscle.
這真是一塊又厚又緊的肌肉。
Hey, sweetie,
can you grab me a beer?
嘿，甜心，你能給我拿一瓶啤酒嗎？
-I'll get you another Heineken.
-Yeah.
－我去給你拿一瓶喜力啤酒。
－好的。
Merry Christmas.
聖誕快來。
And how about you, Tiffany,
what did you get for Christmas?
你呢,蒂弗妮？
你聖誕節得到了什麼？
I got this Mikimoto pearl necklace.
我得到了這串御木本珍珠項鏈。
But next year I'm gonna ask
Santa for breast implants...
但是明年我想讓聖誕老人送我隆胸手術...
...because I'm impatient
with my body.
...因為我對我身體沒耐心了。
Hey, Tiffany. Wanna know
what I got? A crushed soul.
嘿，蒂弗妮，想知道我得到了什麼嗎？
一個破碎的靈魂。
You mentioned that earlier.
你剛才提到了。
-So good.
-Oh, gosh!
－那好吧。
－哦，天哪！
It's gone into a real bad spasm,
so I put a yoga move on her.
這次是真的嚴重痙攣，
所以我在她身上使用了瑜珈動作。
--grant me this one,
because I was pretty wasted.
--給我這個，因為我被折騰太厲害了。
So I put my lips
around that breathalyzer...
所以我把咬住測醉器 ...
...and I saw those numerals pop up:
...然後我看到這些數字跳了出來：
0.079.
So I started going to Chad
Michael Murray's Christmas party.
然後我開始去查德·邁克爾·墨瑞的聖誕晚會。
I think that was the year.
And just driving--
我認為那就是過年。
然後開車--
I have to interrupt you. Robert, while
the children are in the living room...
我必須要打斷你。羅伯特，趁孩子們都在起居室的時候...
...I think this would be a good time
to make our announcement.
...我認為那是宣佈好時機。
-What's going on?
-It's over.
－怎麼了？
－一切都結束了。
I'm gonna be moving in
with my friend Jack Handle...
我要搬去和傑克.翰斗一起住...
...and Nancy found a townhouse
in the city.
...南希也在城裡找一處市內住宅。
What is this? What's happening?
怎麼是這樣？怎麼回事？
What Robert is trying to say
is that we are getting a divorce.
羅伯特想說的是我們要離婚了。
-Don't do this.
-No. No!
－別這樣。
－不，不！
-I could've called this one.
-No.
－我本可以預料到的。
－不。
-Yeah.
-ls it our fault?
－是的。
－是我們的錯嗎？
-ls it because we were bad?
-No. No.
－是不是因為我們太差勁了？
－不。不。
The main thing that
Robert and I talked about...
我和羅伯特談論的主要內容是...
...is that we did not want you two
to blame yourselves.
...我們不想讓你們太自責。
-What can we do to fix it?
-Dale, honey, are you okay?
－我們做什麼能挽回？
－戴爾，親愛的，你還好嗎？
-Why are you calling him "honey"?
-I cannot stress this enough:
－為什麼你稱他為「親愛的」？
－我要再強調一下：
-lt is not your fault.
-Whose fault is it?
－那不是你們的錯。
－那是誰的錯？
-Fuck it, I wanna fucking know!
-Let's cut the shit.
－該死，我想他媽的知道！
－讓我們廢話少說。
-lt is directly your fault.
-Robert.
－那就是你們的錯。
－羅伯特。
You destroyed my boat.
你們毀了我的船。
You beat me up in your sleep...
你們在睡夢中揍了我...
...and worst of all, you made
Nancy and I resent each other.
...最糟糕的是，你們讓我和南希互相怨恨。
-lt is absolutely 1 50 percent your fault!
-Of course it's their fault.
－這絕對150％的是你們的錯。
－當然是他們的錯。
They're the world's biggest dickheads,
and they're living in your house.
他們是世界上最大的白癡，
並且他們就住在你們的房子裡。
-Shut up, Derek.
-I'm sorry, but that--
－閉嘴，德裡克。
－對不起，但那--
Please don't cry like that.
Please don't, Brennan.
請不要那樣哭泣。請別那樣，布倫南。
-Mommy!
-Dale!
－媽媽！
－戴爾！
I told you that they would feel
completely to blame.
我告訴過你他們會非常自責的。
-Oh, let's grow up.
-I think I'm going to throw up.
－哦，讓我們成熟點。
－我想要吐。
-I think I'm gonna throw up...
-Don't throw up.
－我想要吐...
－不要吐。
...all the nice dinner that I had.
I'm gonna throw it up.
...把我吃的美食都吐出來。
我要都吐出來。
-You're not gonna throw up.
-He's gonna throw up.
－你不會吐的。
－他要吐了。
-Come on.
-My God, he threw up. Oh, this is ugly.
－別這樣。
－我的天，他吐了。哦，好噁心。
-Hey, guys. Guys.
-This is not nice!
－嘿，夥計們。夥計們。
－這不好。
-All right, dipshits. Right here.
-Stop it, Derek.
－好了，蠢貨。這邊看。
－住手，德裡克。
-One, two, three....
-I don't want my picture taken now.
－一、二、三...
－我不想現在拍照。
Good luck, and remember, I need you
out of this house by tomorrow.
祝你好運。記住，
明天之前你要搬出這個房子。
No exceptions.
你也不例外。
If there's anything you need,
anything that you boys need...
假如你們需要什麼...
...you just give me a call. Okay?
It's all right.
... 給我打電話。好嗎？
好了。
Hey. Are you awake?
嘿。你醒著了嗎？
Yeah.
是的。
I can't believe we actually
have to move out of this house.
我無法相信我們真的要搬出這個房子。
I know. I feel bad.
我知道。我感覺很糟。
Hey, you know,
we don't have to whisper anymore.
嘿，你知道，我們不用再耳語了。
Mom and Dad aren't here.
媽和爸都不在。
Yeah, but can we keep
doing it, though?
是的，但我們能繼續那樣嗎？
It helps me pretend that they are.
那會使我覺得他們都在。
You must feel just terrible.
你肯定感覺很糟糕。
-I mean, I know I feel bad.
-Yeah.
－我的意思是，我知道我感覺很糟。
－是的。
But I can't imagine how you feel...
但是我無法想像你當時的感覺...
...after my dad looked
right at you and said...
...我父親盯著你說...
...it's all your fault
that they broke up.
...他們離婚全是你的錯。
That's funny, because my mom said:
那太有趣了，因為我媽媽說：
"lf that curly-headed fuck Dale
wasn't here...
「假如那個卷頭髮的該死的戴爾不在的話...
...everything would be perfect."
...一切將會很完美。」
-You take that back.
-No way. It's your fault.
－你收回你的話。
－沒門。那是你的錯。
You know what your problem is?
你知道你的毛病是什麼嗎？
You live in a fantasy land.
You refuse to get a job...
你生活在幻想中。
你拒絕工作...
...and you don't know what it's like
to work for something.
...你不知道工作是什麼樣子的。
You don't take responsibility for
your actions. This is all your fault!
你對你的行為不負責任。全都是你的錯！
Well, you're a mama's boy
who's too chicken to sing in public!
哦，你因為膽怯不敢在人面前唱歌，
你就是媽媽的小男孩！
Yeah, that's right.
是的，這就對了。
Run away, little boy,
because you know it's true.
快逃，小男孩，因為你知道我說的都是真的。
Just avoid everything.
你逃避一切。
What are you doing?
你要幹什麼？
-Dale broke up Mom and Dad
-Motherfucker!
－戴爾拆散了媽媽和爸爸。
－婊子養的！
Dale broke up Mom and Dad
戴爾拆散了媽媽和爸爸
-Dale broke up Mom and--
-Brennan!
－戴爾拆散了媽媽和--
－布倫南！
Get up, Brennan,
I know you're faking. Get up!
起來，布倫南，我知道你是裝的。起來！
Get up!
起來！
Brennan?
布倫南？
It's just like Cold Case Files.
就像《鐵證懸案》。
People die every day.
每天都有人死。
Give him a proper burial
in an unmarked grave....
把他體面的葬在一個不顯眼的墳墓裡...
-Brennan! You're alive! Oh, my God.
-I know.
－布倫南！你還活著！哦，我的上帝。
－我知道。
I'm alive.
我活著。
-You were dead. I saw you die!
-I was faking.
－你死了。我親眼看見的。
－我裝的。
I used ninja focus
to slow my heart rate down.
我用了忍者神龜聚焦法減慢了心率。
-What are you doing?
-I'm burying you.
－你要幹什麼？
－我要埋了你。
-I'm alive. Brennan, I'm alive.
-You're waking the neighbors!
－我還活著。布倫南，我還活著。
－你把鄰居都要吵醒了！
-Shut up!
-No. No.
－閉嘴！
－不。不。
-Now I'm gonna play your drum set.
-Help me.
－現在我要去玩你的鼓。
－幫幫我。
Close your eyes.
Let the dirt just shower over you.
閉上眼睛。
讓土壤給你淋浴吧。
This is your fault.
這是你的錯。
Oh, I'm exhausted.
I'm gonna sleep good tonight.
哦，我累壞了。
我今晚要去好好睡一覺。
-Don't you touch my drums!
-Zombie!
－別動我的鼓！
－蛇神！
Zombie! Zombie!
蛇神！蛇神！
Get off me, zombie.
放開我，蛇神。
Get off.
滾開。
I'm late for school.
我上學要遲到了。
I will kiss you right on the mouth,
Kenny Rogers.
我要吻你的嘴，肯尼 羅傑斯。
-Just get off me.
-Hey.
－離我遠點。
－嘿。
So I guess it's really over.
我猜真的一切都完了。
I'd say you trying to bury me alive
pretty much did it.
我想說你試圖想活埋我。
You know what I just realized?
你知道我剛才意識到什麼嗎？
You've been the one
dragging me down.
你就是那個一直使我墮落的人。
Now I'm gonna go out and I'm gonna
get a job and an apartment...
現在我要走出去，找份工作，找個房子...
...and then I'm gonna get Mom
and Dr. Doback back together.
...然後把媽媽和多巴克先生重新撮合在一起。
I'm gonna be the hero,
and you can suck on it.
我將會成為那個英雄，
而你等著羨慕我吧。
My life was perfect
before you came here.
在你來之前我的生活非常完美。
Me and my dad had a perfect setup,
and you wrecked it.
我和父親的關係非常融洽，
而你毀了一切。
Hey.
嘿。
We're no longer brothers.
我們不再是兄弟了。
We never were.
We were stepbrothers.
我們從來都不是。
我們是異父異母的兄弟。
-That was one of your best.
-These balls fucking suck.
－那是你最好的球之一。
－這些球真他媽的爛。
All right.
好的。
Well, well, well,
look who's here, boys.
哇，哇，哇，先生們，看看誰來了。
Can you give me a job, please?
能給我份工作嗎，求你了？
TJ, get an office pool going.
TJ，設個辦公室賭局。
Give Ken-Doll Crotch here
two weeks, tops.
打賭他最多呆兩個星期。
Dr. Angel Face,
I just wanted to say thank you...
天使一樣的醫生，我只是想說謝謝...
...for meeting me
on such short notice.
...您這麼快就安排了見我。
-Don't call me Angel Face.
-I apologize.
－別叫我天使。
－我道歉。
I'm very alone right now, and the thing
I wanna ask you to help me--
我現在非常孤獨，我想讓你幫幫我--
To show me how I can be
a grown-up.
--讓我明白怎麼樣做一個成年人。
Do I carry my
high-school diploma around?
我要帶著我的高中文憑闖蕩嗎？
What do you do with your hair?
你怎麼打理的頭髮？
What happens if there's
inclement weather?
在狂風暴雨的天氣裡會發生什麼呢？
Where do you--?
What do you wear?
你在哪--？
你穿的什麼？
Can you wash clothes
in the dishwasher?
你能在洗碗機裡洗衣服嗎？
I notice that there's a long gap
in your job history...
我注意到在你的工作經歷中
有一段長長的空白...
...and it said for 22 years...
...上面顯示是22年...
...you went Kerouac
on everyone's ass?
...你亂交找樂子？
I'm gonna be honest with you.
I really need a job.
我必須要和你說實話。
我真的很需要一份工作。
And I will take any position,
as long as it doesn't involve...
什麼工作都行，只要不是...
...having sex with old ladies
for money or bear traps.
...為錢和老女人或者帶牙套的婊子做愛。
-Those are my two bugaboos.
-All right, got it.
－這是我的兩個恐懼。
－好，明白了。
There's a catering business,
there's a temp job open.
有個餐飲店，正好有個臨時工作空缺。
And you get to play with fire.
並且，你要去和火打交道了。
What do you want?
This is my online-poker time.
你想幹什麼？
這是我的在線玩撲克時間。
I'm ready to take on
the Catalina Wine Mixer.
我想承辦卡特琳納島酒會。
Slow down there, Speed Racer.
慢點，極速賽車手。
I know what it entails,
and I'm ready to nail it.
我知道要怎麼做，
並且我已經準備好了做好它。
I want it, okay?
I want the Catalina Wine Mixer.
我想做，明白嗎？
我想承辦卡特琳納島酒會。
-Yo, yo.
-Hey, D-man.
－吆，吆。
－嘿，達人。
-You tell him what's up?
-I sure did.
－你告訴他你現在要幹什麼了嗎？
－當然了。
-Hey.
－嘿。
Your brother wants a shot
at the Catalina Wine Mixer.
你哥哥想嘗試一下卡特琳納島酒會。
I'm ready, walking tall.
我已經準備好了，胸有成竹。
You're ready to run with the bulls?
你準備好與公牛賽跑了嗎？
I've been earning and burning,
snapping necks and cashing checks.
我一直都是賺錢、很快的花掉、
買便宜貨和兌換支票。
Screw it, let's let him do it.
It's a win-win for me...
媽的，讓他做。
對我來說這是雙贏...
-...because if you fuck up, Brennan...
-Yeah?
－...因為如果你搞砸了，布倫南...
－怎樣？
...I get to fire your ass. But if you pull
it off, I look like a genius to the board.
...我會炒了你。但如果你成功了，
對於董事會來講，我看起來就會像個天才。
-Okay?
-I get it.
－明白了？
－明白。
Brennan, here's the thing.
布倫南，情況是這樣的。
It's the Catalina fucking
Wine Mixer, okay?
這是卡特琳納島酒會，明白？
Are you saying "pow"?
What are you saying?
你說「炮」？
你在說什麼？
It's the biggest helicopter-leasing
event in the Western Hemisphere...
這是西半球最大直升機租賃事件...
...since 1 997.
...自1997年以來。
-Why does he keep doing that?
-I have to sell or lease...
－他為什麼老那樣？
－我必須要賣或者租賃...
...at least 80 choppers
to make my nut.
...至少80架直升飛機才能抵消我的運營費用。
And you mess with my nut, Brennan,
Randy here is gonna eat your dick.
如果你搞砸了，布倫南，
蘭迪會吃了你的命根子。
Like Kobayashi.
象小林（一著名飲食冠軍）一樣。
I've seen him do it.
我已經見識過他那樣做了。
You've seen him eat a penis?
你見過他吃一根命根子？
It was in international waters,
so they couldn't prosecute him.
那是在國際水域，所以他們不能起訴他。
I tell you now, I'll nail it.
I'll pull it off, okay?
我現在告訴你，我會做好的。
我會成功的，可以了？
Wait a second,
why do you want this so bad?
等一下，你為什麼如此想要這次機會？
Trying to get Mom and Dad
back together or something?
想使爸媽復合還是其它的什麼事情？
-Why do I want this?
-Yeah.
－為什麼我想要這個？
－是的。
Because I wanna make bank, bro.
I wanna get ass.
因為我想攢錢，老弟。
我想幹活。
And I wanna drive a Range Rover.
我想開一輛攬勝陸虎。
Okay, well, you better, Brennan.
好了，布倫南，好好幹。
This is the fucking
Catalina Wine Mixer.
這是他媽的卡特琳納島酒會。
Nancy. Hi.
南希。嗨。
Hi. What are you doing here?
嗨。你在這裡做什麼？
Well, Dale's working the function.
嗯，戴爾在其中擔任一定職責。
Guys, this is supposed to be jicama,
not bok choy.
夥計們，這應該是涼薯，不是白菜。
Sorry, folks.
抱歉，各位。
And I got an invitation from Brennan.
我是受了布倫南的邀請。
Can you believe
Brennan put all this together?
你能相信是布倫南組織了這一切嗎？
And now here we all are in Catalina.
現在我們都在聖卡塔利娜島。
-It's funny, huh?
-Yeah, it's funny.
－很有趣，啊？
－對，很有趣。
-Hey, hey, hey.
-Hey.
－嘿，嘿，嘿。
－嘿。
Not bad. You're nailing it.
不錯。你幹的很不錯。
-Thanks, Randy. That means a lot.
-Yeah.
－謝謝，蘭迪。那對我很重要。
I don't know what it is...
我不知道那是什麼...
...but I wanna deliver one of these
right in your suck hole.
...但是我想讓你知道一點。
-ls there anything I can do?
-No. Not really. It's your face.
－有什麼我可以做的嗎？
－不。其實沒有。是你的臉。
Again, you're doing great, man.
The Catalina Wine Mixer.
再說一次，你做的很棒，老兄。
卡特琳納島酒會
We're all having a great time,
having fun.
我們正在享受快樂的時光，開心點。
You pulled it off.
But if you don't change your face...
你成功了。
但如果你不改變你的臉的話...
-...I'm gonna change it for you.
-Okay. Okay.
－...我就要替你改變了。
－好。好。
All I can do is take that in,
consider it...
我能做的就是體會你說的，考慮一下...
...and I'll just do my best version
of whatever I think that would be.
...盡我可能做到我想像中的最好。
I don't even hear you,
your face is driving me nuts.
我幾乎都聽不見你說話，
你的臉都要把我逼瘋了。
-Thanks again, though.
-Oh, tits. Hold on.
－但是，再一次謝謝你。
－哦，小妞。失陪。
-Hey. Hello, Catalina Wine Mixer.
-Hi.
－嘿。大家好，卡特琳納島酒會。
－嗨。
How are you? We are Uptown Girl.
大家好嗎？我們是街區女孩組合。
We are California's preeminent
1 980s Billy Joel cover band.
我們來自加利福尼亞，
是翻唱80年代比利.喬爾的歌曲的優秀樂隊。
"Piano Man"!
「鋼琴師」！
What did I just say, man?
我剛才說什麼來著，老兄？
All right, we don't play that...
好了，我們不表演那個...
...so let's keep it in the '80s
and let's keep it fun.
...讓我們回到80年代，盡情享受吧。
You having a good time?
你們開心嗎？
I hope you are,
because sometimes life can be tough.
我希望你們開心，
因為生活有時可能很艱辛。
And I know that sometimes
it's hard to "Keeping the Faith."
並且我知道有時很難「保持信仰」。
You guys seem to be hitting it off.
看起來你們相處的不錯。
Oh, honey.
哦，寶貝。
Oh, my God,
this is the greatest party.
哦，我的天，這是我見過最棒的晚會。
-Hello, Robert.
-Way to go.
－你好，羅伯特。
－幹的真棒。
-Brennan, this is fantastic.
-Way to go.
－布倫南，真難以置信。
－幹的真棒。
So impressed.
真了不起。
-Hi, Dad. Hi, Nancy.
-Hi, Dale.
－嗨，爸。嗨，南希。
－嗨，戴爾。
-Hey, Brennan.
-It's good to see you.
－嘿，布倫南。
－見到你很高興。
Thanks for hiring
our catering company.
謝謝你僱傭我們餐飲公司。
Easy decision. You guys have
a outstanding track record.
小事一樁。你們有很好的過往業績。
-Just like old times, huh?
-Right, it really is.
－就像原來一樣，不是嗎?
－是的，真的很像。
You still have your
night-vision goggles?
你的夜視鏡還有嗎？
No, no. No, I had to sell those
to pay for car insurance.
不，不，不。我賣了付車險了。
How about you?
You still breaking boards...
你呢？依然破板子...
...or kicking holes in pumpkins
or anything?
...在南瓜上踢洞之類的嗎？
No.
不。
But I did start taking baby aspirin
to reduce my risk for heart attack.
但是我開始服用嬰兒阿司匹林
來降低得心臟病的幾率了。
That makes sense.
Gotta keep an eye on it, you know.
很有道理。
你知道的，一定要注意身體。
-Knock off the sweets.
-Thank you.
－戒掉甜食。
－謝謝。
It's a truly funny observation.
這真是一個非常有趣的慶典。
Yeah.
是的。
Dale, the empanadas
are starting to sweat.
戴爾，肉餡餅開始冒汽了。
Okay. I better run.
好了。我要走了。
-It's good to see you, Brennan.
-You too.
－很高興見到你，布倫南。
－我也一樣。
-Take care, be well. Take care, Dad.
-Okay, buddy.
－保重，身體要健康。保重，爸。
－好的，兒子。
-It's great to talk to him.
-Yeah.
－和他說話真好。
－是的。
I gotta go too.
我也不得不走了。
We should do this again.
I think it was very constructive.
我們應該下次再聚聚。
我認為這是卓有成效的。
-Maybe grab a bite to eat?
-Sure.
－也許你們可以拿點吃的？
－當然。
-Go to Outback Steakhouse.
-Okay.
－下次去澳拜牛排屋。
－好。
I've grown very fond of that place.
我越來越喜歡那地方了。
Thank you for coming.
謝謝你能來。
Great to see you.
見到你很高興。
It was very nice to see you, Robert.
羅伯特，見到你太棒了。
I think Brennan organized this
whole thing to get us back together.
我認為布倫南組織這一切就是想讓我們重新在一起。
You have to excuse me.
I think that I just might cry.
你要原諒我。
我想我要哭了。
It's the funniest thing. Bye-bye.
這是最可笑的事情。拜拜。
"Start the Fire," buddy!
老兄，「放火」！
Come on, man. Play something
from The Stranger!
來吧，老兄。
唱點「陌生人」樂隊的歌。
We strictly do '80s Joel music, sir.
我們只唱80年代喬爾的音樂，先生。
'80s Billy Joel doo-wop sucks!
80年代比利的調子是狗屎！
Hey, listen, motherfucker,
we only sing '80s Joel!
嘿，聽著，婊子養的，
我們只唱80年代喬爾的歌。
So take your skank hooker wife
and get the fuck out of here!
帶著你醜陋的婊子老婆滾出這兒！
Shit.
媽的。
-What's wrong?
-All right. "What's wrong?"
－怎麼著？
－好吧。「怎麼著？」
Get him out of here.
Get his ass out of here!
把他拉走。
讓他滾開！
Hey.
嘿。
Hey, great job, fuck face. You just
busted my nut. This party's shot.
嘿，幹的不錯，我靠. 你搞砸了場子。
這個酒會要報廢了。
Just relax. I didn't realize
he would say these things.
放鬆點。我不知道他會說那些。
You know what?
You cost me money.
你知道什麼？
你讓我損失了錢。
So this isn't even
a judgment call, man.
所以這不公平，老兄。
-You're Audi 5000, my friend.
-Derek, can't we talk about this?
－你要走人了，我的朋友。
－德裡克，我們不能再談談嗎？
No.
不。
-Hey.
-Shit.
－嘿。
－該死。
-ls everything okay?
-No. He just fired me.
－一切還好嗎？
－不，他剛剛解雇了我。
What happened to the music?
音樂怎麼回事？
The band left. The guy freaked out.
樂隊離開了。那個傢伙失控了。
Derek fired me.
德裡克炒了我。
-It's no big deal.
-Robert, you don't get it.
－沒什麼大不了的。
－羅伯特，你不明白。
It's the Catalina Wine Mixer!
這是卡特琳納島酒會！
People have killed
to be in the position I'm in.
人們瘋了的想要我這個職位。
-He's right. It's a big deal.
-Here's a thought:
－他是對的。沒什麼大不了的。
－我有一個想法：
I see an empty stage.
我看到一個空空的舞台。
I see drums, I see a drummer.
我看到鼓，還有一個鼓手。
I see a microphone,
and I see a singer.
我看到了一個麥克風，還有一個歌手。
-Dad, come on.
-What?
－爸，算了吧。
－怎麼了？
-We gave that stuff up.
-We don't do that.
－我們已經放棄唱歌了。
－我們不去。
Listen to me.
Dale, look, when I was a kid...
聽著，戴爾，當我還是個孩子時...
...when I was a little boy,
I always wanted to be a dinosaur.
...當我還是個小孩子的時候，我總是想成為一隻恐龍。
I wanted to be a Tyrannosaurus rex
more than anything.
我想成為一隻暴龍勝過任何事情。
I made my arms short
and I roamed the backyard...
我縮著胳膊，在後院遊蕩...
...and I chased the neighborhood cats,
and I growled and I roared.
...我追趕鄰居家的貓，
我嗥叫 ，我吼叫。
Everybody knew me
and was afraid of me.
每個人都知道我並害怕我。
And then one day, my dad said:
然後有一天，我爸爸對我說：
"Bobby, you're 1 7. It's time
to throw childish things aside."
「兒子，你已經17了。
是把孩子氣的東西丟到一邊的時候了」
And I said, "Okay, Pop."
我說：「好的，爸。」
But he didn't really say that, he said,
"Stop being a dinosaur and get a job."
但是他沒有真的那樣說，而是說：
「別再做一隻恐龍了，去找份工作」。
But, you know, I thought to myself,
"I'll go to medical school...
但是，你知道，我想：
「我去上醫學院...」
...I'll practice for a little while,
and then I'll come back to it."
"...干段時間，然後再回來做恐龍"
-Dad--
-How is that a skill?
－爸--
－怎麼做只恐龍的？
But I forgot how to do it.
但是我忘記怎麼去做了。
You're human.
你是人。
-You could never be a dinosaur.
-Yeah.
－你永遠都不可能是只恐龍。
－是的。
Hey, I lost it.
嘿，我把它丟了。
-Dad, what's the point?
-Yeah.
－爸，你想要說什麼？
－是的。
The point is
don't lose your dinosaur.
我想說永遠都不要丟掉你的恐龍。
Yeah. You know, I hated
the way you guys were before.
是的。你們知道，我討厭你們以前的德性。
I mean, I hated you.
我是說，我討厭你們。
But it just kills me to see you
so crushed and normal.
但是看到你們如此意志消沉和正常我更難受。
Listen to me, don't listen to me...
聽我的，不聽我的...
...Prestige Worldwide,
that's what you gotta do.
...環球聲譽，那是你們要去做的。
-You're saying we should go for it.
-That's what I'm saying.
－你是說我們應該追求夢想。
－那正是我的意思。
What do you think, Brennan?
你認為怎麼樣，布倫南？
I'm so scared right now.
I'm gonna do what's sensible:
現在我很害怕。我要去做明智的事情：
I'm gonna file for unemployment...
我要去申請失業...
...and I'm gonna try to get a job
at Enterprise Rent-A-Car.
...我要去在汽車租賃公司找份工作。
Because they got
a excellent corporate structure...
因為他們有著良好的公司結構...
...and they give you the tools
to be your own boss.
...他們會給你自己當老闆的跳板。
My dad's right.
我爸爸是對的。
This isn't me.
這不是我。
I'm fucking miserable.
I had to get up at 1 0:00 this morning.
我他媽的很悲慘。
我不得不每天早晨10點起床。
And even though
I just got a tidal wave of nerves...
儘管我剛才非常緊張...
...I'm going up on that stage...
...我還是要走上那舞台...
...and I'm gonna make beautiful music
for a sad world.
...我要為這悲慘的世界演奏出美麗的音樂。
-Dale....
-That's the boy I know.
－戴爾...
－這才是我認識的兒子。
This crowd's gonna eat him alive.
人們會生吃了他的。
Wait, what's he doing up there?
等下，他在那裡幹什麼？
Somebody get him
off the fucking stage!
快去把他從他媽的舞台上拉下來。
Hi. How you doing?
嗨。你們好嗎？
My name's Dale Doback,
and I hope you like to kick it.
我叫戴爾.多巴克，
希望你們會喜歡。
Oh, go get them, Dale!
哦，你是最棒的，戴爾！
Boats and ho's
歌詞：Boats and ho's
Get off the stage, you dick!
下來，你這個混蛋！
Stop yelling at him.
別朝他嚷。
-Terrible!
-Terrible.
－太可怕了！
He's a human being.
他是個人。
Dale has a mangina
戴爾有個女人下體。
戴爾有個女人下體
No.
不。
Gotta have me my boats and ho's
歌詞Gotta have me my boats and ho's
He's up there alone, Brennan.
He's up there alone.
他一個人在那孤軍奮戰，布倫南。
他一個人在那孤軍奮戰。
Gotta have me my boats and ho's
歌詞：Gotta have me my boats and ho's
-You suck!
-What are you doing, Brennan?
－垃圾！
－你要幹什麼，布倫南？
Gotta have me my....
歌詞：Gotta have me my....
Brennan, no!
布倫南，不！
-What did you do?
-Oh, Jesus, Nancy.
－你在做什麼？
－哦，上帝，南希。
I couldn't stand to see him like that.
I miss my son.
我無法容忍看他變成那個樣子。
我想我的兒子。
All right. Let me go for a few bars.
Come in soft, but then finish strong.
好吧。讓我唱幾段。
舒緩的切入，強勁的結束。
-Okay. Hey, Brennan?
-Yeah.
－好。嘿，布倫南？
－是的。
-Thanks for coming up.
-You got it, Dragon.
－謝謝你能來。
－你說對了，巨龍。
We got a little change coming up.
情況有點小小的變化。
It's my main man Brennan.
這是主唱布倫南。
Boats and ho's
歌詞：Boats and ho's。
-You did it, Derek.
-I made a kite fly.
－你成功了，德裡克。
－我把風箏飛起來了。
Brennan, you're the best
big brother ever!
布倫南，你是最好最好的哥哥。
--floor mats. The ones that match
the seats, and I kind of wanted--
--地毯。那些和座椅很配的地毯，
我有點想--
I traveled 500 miles
to give you my seed.
我走了500英里就是要和你做愛。
Lumberjack!
伐木匠！
Rock the fuck
out of those drums, Dale!
把鼓擊神了，戴爾！
I'm sorry.
對不起。
-We're Prestige Worldwide!
-Prestige Worldwide!
－我們是環球聲譽！
－環球聲譽！
-Fucking Catalina Wine Mixer.
-It's the fucking Catalina Wine Mixer.
－了不起的卡特琳納島酒會。
－這真是屆了不起的卡特琳納島酒會。
It's the fucking Catalina Wine Mixer.
這真是屆了不起的卡特琳納島酒會。
Brennan, that was sublime.
布倫南，非常棒。
Amazing.
We are so proud of you both.
了不起。
我們都為你們倆感到驕傲。
-Thank you.
-lncredible.
－謝謝你們。
－難以置信。
-Thank you so much.
-Hey.
－非常感謝你們。
－嘿。
So I made my quota.
Yeah, we sold a shit-ton of copters.
我完成了配額。
是的，我們賣出了大批的直升機。
-That's so good.
-Yeah.
－那很不錯。
－是的。
Look, I'm not great at
this Hallmark stuff...
聽著，我並不善於識別人才...
...but, Brennan,
when I look at you now...
...但是，布倫南，當我現在看著你...
...I don't wanna kick you
in the head quite as much.
...我不那麼想踢你腦袋了。
Thanks, man.
謝謝，老兄。
-That was beautiful.
-That was nice.
－那太棒了。
－不錯。
Yeah.
是的。
-What do we do now?
-We could hug.
－我們現在做點什麼？
－我們可以擁抱一下。
Yeah, you'd like that, faggot.
Sorry. I'm--
是的，你就喜歡那樣，「同志」。
對不起。我--
Okay.
好吧。
-It's okay.
-Okay.
－沒關係的。
－好的。
-That's what we've been looking for.
-That's the ticket.
－這正是我們一直都在尋找的。
－這正是所需要的東西。
It's fantastic.
太不可思議了。
We've never done anything like that,
so you can't expect it to be perfect.
我們從來沒那樣做過，
所以我們沒法指望很完美。
It was good.
很好。
-Felt good.
-Gotten close to a hug.
－感覺不錯。
－算是一個擁抱。
-Hello, Brennan. Hi.
-Denise. Hey.
－你好，布倫南。嗨。
－戴妮絲。嘿。
Robert, Mom, Derek,
this is my girlfriend, Denise.
羅伯特，媽媽，德裡克，
這是我女朋友，戴妮絲。
-Hi. How are you?
-Actually, I'm his therapist.
－嗨。你好。
－實際上，我是他的心理醫生。
-We are in absolutely no way dating.
-Right.
－絕對不是約會。
－是的。
Brennan told me he was going to
hurl his body off a helicopter...
布倫南告訴我他要從一架直升飛機上跳下來...
...into shark-infested waters...
...跳到鯊魚出沒的海域...
...so I had a legal obligation
to be here.
...所以我有法律義務到這裡。
I get it.
我明白了。
Don't wanna appear too eager,
and that is a good strategy too.
別想表現的太急切，
那也是一個很好的策略。
You are an enabler.
You think you're helping...
你就是一個推動器。
你認為自己在幫忙...
-...but you're not.
-And you are a keeper.
－...但實際上不是。
－你是他的監護人。
What'd you think?
你怎麼認為？
Brennan, I thought
you were incredibly brave.
布倫南，我認為你非同尋常的勇敢。
And I mean that...
我是說...
...in strictly the most clinical
and professional sense possible...
...從最嚴格的科學和職業角度講...
...with no emotional,
intimate, sexual...
...不摻雜任何情感、私人和性別...
...or any other undertones
that you could possibly infer.
...或其它你可以推斷的任何因素。
God, you're gonna make me cry.
上帝，你都要把我弄哭了。
What poem is that from?
Is that James Joyce?
那出自什麼詩？
是詹姆斯·喬伊斯的嗎？
Alice...
愛麗斯...
-...I like making sex with you.
-Yeah.
－...我喜歡和你做愛。
－是的。
I do. But you're also married.
我喜歡。但是你結婚了。
It's over.
一切都結束了。
This is crazy. I'm a mother.
這太瘋狂了。我是一個母親。
I have two children,
I have a husband, a beautiful home.
我有兩個孩子，一個丈夫，一個美麗的家。
-I can't be fucking around with you.
-lt was fun. It was fun, right?
－我不能和你呆在一起。
－我們當時很開心。很開心，不是嗎？
-lt was fun while it lasted.
-I'm glad. All right, well, good luck.
－那時候很開心。
－我很高興。好吧，祝你好運。
-No.
-Oh, my God, Dale!
－不。
－哦，我的天哪，戴爾!
-Please don't leave me.
-Oh, my God. Look at that whale.
－請別離開我。
－哦，天哪。看那頭鯨。
Where?
哪兒？
Dale!
戴爾！
So I was with Seal...
我當時和海豹特種部隊...
...and we were just taking a chopper
up to Everest base camp...
...搭乘一架直升飛機去珠穆朗瑪峰的營地...
-...and the plot to my Sherpa--
-Derek. Derek.
－...關於夏爾巴人的情節--
－德裡克。德裡克。
-Sorry. Okay.
-Remember, we talked about this.
－抱歉。好的。
－記著，我們說好的。
Dale, Brennan.
Tell me about the karaoke business.
戴爾，布倫南。
談談卡拉OK的生意。
Really great, Dad.
Yeah. We call it Karaoke 'n' Roll.
真的很棒，爸爸。
是的，我們把它稱為卡拉OK搖滾。
We got six bars, three restaurants,
and two more wanna sign up.
我們簽訂了六個酒吧，三個餐館，
還有兩個想要加入。
-So it's booming.
-Fantastic.
－所以前景光明。
－棒極了。
Most karaoke it's,
"Open to everyone.
大多數卡拉Ok都是，「向每一個人開放。「
-Hey, just get up and have fun."
-Not you guys.
—「嘿，起來，玩得開心。」
－你們不是。
If you can't sing, just sit down.
That's our motto.
假如你不會唱，就坐下來。
這是我們的座右銘。
-It's the big leagues.
-You guys are doing so great.
－這是最大的聯盟。
－你們做的真了不起。
Guys, I have a little Christmas
surprise for Dale and Brennan.
夥計們，我有一個小小的聖誕驚喜給戴爾和布倫南。
-You wanna see it?
-Yes!
－你們想看看嗎？
－當然！
-You bet!
-Let's go look at it! Come on.
－沒錯！
－讓我們去看看！來吧。
-Don't peek.
-I smell cookies.
－別偷看。
－我聞見點心了。
Be patient. No, no. No, no.
耐心點。不，不。不，不。
-Just a pinata, isn't it?
-Be patient. Be patient.
－是個皮納塔，對嗎？
－耐心點。耐心點。
-Be patient.
-Did you get me a tiger, Dad?
－耐心點。
－你給我弄了隻老虎嗎，爸？
Okay, open your eyes.
好了，睜開眼看看。
Merry Christmas.
聖誕快樂。
Holy shit!
天哪！
Dad, I can't believe
you put the boat in the tree!
爸爸，難以置信你把船放到了樹上！
This is amazing!
太讓人吃驚了！
-It's The Gilded Lady. She lives!
-I can't believe it.
－是Gilded Lady。它還有用！
－我簡直不敢相信。
-How'd you get it up here?
-Oh, Robert, it's so great.
－你怎麼把它弄上去的？
－哦，羅伯特，這太棒了。
-Pirate hats!
－海盜帽！
-Hustlers!
－好色客雜誌！
Dad, that was so thoughtful!
爸，你想的真周到。
-Crossbows!
－弓箭！
You guys finally came to your senses
and got us something cool.
你們終於找回自己的感覺了，
給了我們真正酷的東西。
You both know this is
completely fucked up, right?
你們倆都知道這整個都亂七八糟，對嗎？
-Yeah.
-Of course.
－是的。
－當然。
But Brennan sure can wear the shit
out of that pirate hat.
但是布倫南卻能從那頂海盜帽中自得其樂。
-Chewbacca masks!
－楚巴卡（《星球大戰》中一角色）面具！
－楚巴卡面具！
It's okay that mine's
not movie-quality.
我的不是電影中的質量，但沒關係。
But he's like, "No, because you drove
my car last week, so I can't get it."
但是他說：「不，因為你上個星期開我的車了，
所以我不會買。」
So I'm like "You're gonna buy it for me
or I'm gonna sock you in the mouth."
所以我就說：「你要給我把它買下來，
否則我就打你的嘴。」
Oh, shit.
哦，該死。
Well, if it isn't Dale Doback
and his little butt buddy.
嗯，如果那不是戴爾.多巴克和他那小狗屎朋友。
Sticks and stones
may break my bones...
棍子和石頭可能會砸爛我的骨頭...
...but I'm gonna kick you repeatedly
in the balls, Gardocki!
...但是我要踢爛你的蛋，卡爾多吉！
Let's get them!
我們去抓住他們！
-Where do you think you're going?
-Home.
－你想要去哪兒？
－回家。
-We got something to show you.
-Come on.
－我們拿了點東西要你看看。
－來吧。
-You see that white dog crap?
-Do you see it?!
－看到那個白色狗屎了嗎？
－看到了嗎？
-Yeah.
-Not too fun down there, is it?
－是的。
－爬在那兒沒多少樂趣，對嗎？
-No.
-You see?
－是的。
－你明白了？
Your actions have consequences!
你的行為會得到報應的！
When you oppress people,
they rise up in a fiery anger!
當你壓迫別人的時候，
他們會極大的憤怒反抗的！
Go home.
回家吧。
We're not like you.
We're grown-ups, motherfucker!
我們不像你。
我們是成年人，婊子養的！
Say hi to your dad.
We went to high school together.
替我向你爸爸打聲招呼。
我們一起上的高中。
The cops'll be here soon.
警察很快就來了。
I guess this is what it feels like
to be grown up.
我想這就是長大的感覺。
Hey.
嘿。
Can I ask you something?
我能問你點事嗎？
Yeah, of course.
當然可以。
You know back when
you first moved in?
你記得你開始搬進來的時候？
Yeah.
是的。
-Did you touch my drum set?
-No, I didn't.
－你動我的鼓了沒有？
－沒，我沒有。
No, really, I won't get mad.
I just wanna know.
不，說真的，我不會生氣的。
我只是想知道。
No, I know.
You said you wouldn't get mad.
不，我知道。
你說你不會生氣的。
I'm saying I didn't do it.
I didn't do it, I never did it.
我說我真的沒有動，從來沒動過。
-Then I owe you an apology.
-No.
－那我欠你一個道歉。
－不。
No, you don't, at all. No.
不，你不欠，根本不欠。
Why wouldn't you take an apology
if you didn't do it?
假如你沒動的話，
你為什麼不接受我的道歉？
Just because I'm cool.
It doesn't matter.
只是因為我酷。
那沒關係。
You got my passport.
你拿了我的護照。
I'm good.
我很好。
Don't worry, not gonna be late.
Don't worry.
別擔心，不會遲到的。
別擔心。